太棒了，夫人，不是吗?
Glorious, madam, isn't it?
是的。
Yes.
我能看看下面那个吗?
Could I see that one down there, please?
啊，是的，的确是这样，夫人。当然可以。
Why, yes, indeed, madam. By all means.
迈耶先生!迈耶先生!
Mr. Meyer! Mr. Meyer!
放我出去!放我出去!
Let me out of here! Let me out of here!
这是什么?有个女人从迈耶公司偷了个手镯然后在第三大道当掉了。打开和关闭。
What's this? Some dame cops a bracelet outta Meyer and Company and hocks it on 3rd Avenue. Open and shut.
第一次进攻吗?不，她有案底。
First offense? No, she's got a record.
这是她第三次犯案。
This is her third offense.
好!好!圣诞节的初犯比老虎肉还硬。
Good! Good! First offender at Christmas time is tougher than tiger meat.
定罪率只有78%
Convictions only 78%
而去年这一比例为82%。
as against 82% last year.
我能处理这个案子吗，老板?我会给你定罪的…你也许能应付得和这些笨蛋一样好。
Can I handle this case, boss? I'll get you a conviction... Well, you could probably handle it as well as some of these dopes.
当合适的案子出现时，我会给你的。
When the right case comes along, I'll give it to you.
打老婆之类的。
Wife beater or something like that.
你的脸不适合起诉一个女人。
Your face isn't right to prosecute a woman.
给我接萨金特。
Get me Sargent.
他的脸有什么是我没有的?
What's his face got that mine hasn't got?
我不知道，但不管是什么，他还没输过我的案子。
I don't know, but whatever it is, he hasn't lost a case for me yet.
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
如果这是办公室，他已经走了。
Well, if this is the office, he's already left.
我可没让你这么说，你个哑铃。
I didn't say to say that, you dumbbell.
我,没有。这不是他的办公室。
My, no. This isn't his office.
你就告诉他有个年轻女人想跟他约个时间。
You just tell him that a young woman wants to make an appointment with him.
这里不是办公室。
This isn't the office.
一位年轻女士想和你预约。
A young woman wants to make an appointment with you.
等一下。
Just a minute.
谁想和萨金特大师说话?
Who all wants to speak to master Sargent?
你的老板。
Your boss.
还好你没有以演戏为生。
It's a good thing you didn't take up the stage for a living.
15分钟后在这里见。
I'll see you down here in 15 minutes.
等一下，我办完马修斯的案子时你跟我说过是啊，但我还要开750英里呢。
Now wait a minute, you told me when I finished up the Matthews case... Yeah, but I got 750 miles to drive.
你妈妈肯定会生气的。
Your mother sure is gonna be mad.
当然，开车的时候睡着了，喝醉了。
Sure, and fall asleep at the wheel and get croaked.
那么，谁在为自己辩护呢?
Well, who's defending?
奥利里。
O'Leary.
饶舌之人?
That windbag?
他会发表葛底斯堡演说和《独立宣言》我会让汤姆在法庭上见你，你中午就能出院。
He'll give us the Gettysburg Address and the Declaration of Independence... I'll have Tom meet you in court and you'll be out of there by noon.
请记住你在和谁说话。
Kindly remember who you're talking to.
别把猪扯进来。
And leave the pigs out of it.
…在审判过程中，以证明被告从迈耶公司拿走了一个有价值的手镯。
...during the course of this trial, to prove that a valuable bracelet was taken from the premises of Meyer and Company by the defendant.
我不喜欢陪审团脸上的笑容!
I don't like the smile on that jury's pan!
所有的陪审团在圣诞节都会心软，汤米。
All juries get softhearted at Christmas, Tommy.
如果你有一个案子要起诉你会看到"世界和平，善待人类"
If you ever get a case to prosecute and you see that "peace on earth, goodwill toward men"
看着他们的眼睛，申请延期。
look come in their eyes, get a continuance.
这个论点多么站不住脚啊!
How flimsy is this argument!
这一切都是在浪费时间，陪审团的女士们先生们，浪费你我的时间。
All this is a waste of time, ladies and gentlemen of the jury, of your time and mine.
我们可以把时间花在最后一分钟的圣诞购物上。
Time we could spend to much better advantage in last minute Christmas shopping.
我知道这就是我想做的。
I know that's what I'd like to be doing.
请法庭允许，我们反对，法官阁下。
May it please the Court, we object, Your Honor.
陪审团的圣诞购物与本案无关。
The jury's Christmas shopping has nothing to do with the case.
反对持续。
Objection sustained.
陪审团不会理会奥利里先生关于圣诞购物的诱人暗示。
The jury will disregard Mr. O'Leary's tempting allusion to Christmas shopping.
很明显，我们都想去圣诞购物。
Quite obviously, we'd all like to be Christmas shopping.
我收回暗指，法官阁下。
I withdraw the allusion, Your Honor.
我说的是浪费时间，是指控方竭尽全力证明安娜-罗斯·马龙，有时也被称为李·利安德……有时被称为很多其他的东西。
When I say there has been a waste of time, I mean that the State has gone to great lengths to prove that Anna-Rose Malone, sometimes known as Lee Leander... Sometimes known as a lot of other things.
…12月3日下午，他带着一只手镯走在第五大道上，这只手镯仍然是迈耶公司的财产。
...did on the afternoon of December 3rd, walk out upon 5th Avenue with a bracelet, which was still the property of Meyer and Company.
为了证明她坦白承认的事。
To prove something she freely admits.
好像这一事实的证据就构成了有罪的证据。
As if the proof of that fact constituted proof of guilt.
事实很简单。
The truth is simple.
手镯是在暂时失去意志和意识的情况下取下的，现在被称为精神分裂症，但以前被称为催眠。
The bracelet was removed during a temporary loss of will and consciousness, now known as schizophrenia, but formerly known as hypnotism.
这个年轻的女孩……"我们不反对"是什么意思?
This young girl... What do you mean "we're not going to object"?
闭嘴。他只是把案子推迟到圣诞节之后。
Shut up. He's just postponed the case till after Christmas.
你怎么知道的?
How do you figure that?
催眠术。
Hypnotism.
售货员给她看了手镯。
The salesman showed her the bracelet.
我劝她把它戴在手腕上。
Urged her to clasp it on her wrist.
请她在更有力的光线下检查一下。
Begged her to examine it under a more powerful light.
然后他找了个借口。
And then he excused himself.
不，这是老把戏!
No, it's an old trick!
这是穷人的诱惑。
This tempting of the poor.
他们说:“把它带回家，戴上几天。”
They say, "Take it home and wear it for a few days."
他们说:“今天下午开着它到处转。
They say, "Drive it around this afternoon.
“明天还回来。”
"Bring it back tomorrow."
哈!“按照你自己的条件去买。”
Ha! "Buy it on your own terms."
想想《浮士德》中梅菲斯托菲勒斯和玛格丽特之间的珠宝场景吧。
Consider the jewel scene between Mephistopheles and Marguerite in Faust.
我希望他不会唱这首歌。
I hope he isn't going to sing it.
手镯在强光下。
The bracelet is under a powerful light.
小女孩盯着它看。
The young girl stares at it.
近了。
Closer.
中央那块巨大的石头在她眼中闪着耀眼的光芒。
The great central stone flashes blindingly in her eyes.
蓝色，绿色，紫色，橙色。
Blue, green, purple, orange.
突然间，颜色消失了。
Suddenly, the colors are gone.
一切都是黑暗。
All is darkness.
但这是什么?
But what is this?
商店在哪里?她的光芒在哪里?
Where is the shop? Where is the light she is under?
她怎么会在第五大道，离迈耶公司几个街区远的地方?
What is she doing on 5th Avenue, blocks away from Meyer and Company?
带着一种恐惧的震颤，她摸了摸自己的手腕，不敢看。
With a thrill of horror, she feels at her wrist, not daring to look.
毫无疑问。
No doubt about it.
然后恐慌。
Then panic.
她转身匆匆走向那家大珠宝店。
She turns and hurries towards the great jewelry store.
他们会相信她吗?
Will they believe her?
恐惧使她的腿变成了铅。
Fear turns her legs to lead.
一个街区，两个街区。
One block, two blocks.
她盲目地走着，撞见了以为她疯了的陌生人。
She goes blindly, bumping into strangers who think she must be crazy.
六块。
Six blocks.
大珠宝店终于来了。
There at last is the great jewelry store.
它的窗户上闪烁着宝石。
Its windows blazing with gems.
但是不，宝石不见了。
But no, the gems are gone.
窗户几乎是空的。
The window is almost bare.
带着一颗沉甸甸的心，她打开了锁。
With a sinking heart, she tries the lock.
它是封闭的。
It's closed.
迈耶公司今晚打烊了。
Meyer and Company have closed for the night.
你不做点什么吗?陪审团已经被收买了。
Ain't you gonna do something? That jury's sold right now.
嘘。等待。
Shh. Wait.
她该怎么办呢?
What was she to do?
夫人，你会怎么做?
What would you do, madam?
那真是个糟糕的地方。
Well, that's certainly a terrible spot to be in.
我想我……
I suppose I...
律师不得向陪审员提问，陪审员不得回答。
Counsel will refrain from questioning the jurors and the jurors will refrain from answering.
我从来没听说过这种事。
I've never heard of such a thing.
请法庭和陪审团原谅。
I beg the court and jury's pardon.
我被迷住了。
I was carried away.
她该怎么办呢?
What was she to do?
突然，灵感来了。电话簿。
Suddenly, an inspiration. The telephone book.
梅耶公司。梅耶公司。
S.A. Meyer and Company. S.A. Meyer and Company.
梅耶检察官肯定住在什么地方，但他似乎没有。
S.A. Meyer must live somewhere, but he doesn't seem to.
“也许是长岛。”
"Maybe it's Long Island."
“S.A.迈耶。S.A.迈耶。”
"S.A. Meyer. S.A. Meyer."
他来了。
Here he is.
S.A.迈耶。
S.A. Meyer.
长岛罗斯林伍德米尔路324号。
324 Woodmere Road, Roslyn, Long Island.
我将乘第一班火车去长岛。
I'll take the first train to Long Island.
我会在晚餐时间到那里。
I'll be there at dinner time.
他会相信我的。他必须相信我。
He'll believe me. He's got to believe me.
他本应该上台的。
He should have been on the stage.
他是。
He was.
但是去长岛需要钱。
But it takes money to go to Long Island.
我去哪里弄钱去长岛告诉迈耶先生发生了什么?
Where will I get the money to go to Long Island and tell Mr. Meyer what happened?
然后一个疯狂的想法。
Then a crazy idea.
我要卖掉手镯，筹钱去长岛。
I'll hawk the bracelet to get the money to go to Long Island.
快，鹰店。
Quick, a hawk shop.
快，华生，拿针。
Quick, Watson, the needle.
我们到了。
Here we are.
一个和蔼可亲的当铺老板。
A nice, cozy pawn broker.
穷人的朋友。
A friend of the poor.
“能给我点钱吗?”
"May I get some money on this, please?"
“好吧，好吧，我想说你可以的，小姑娘。
"Well, well, I should say you could, young woman.
“你从哪儿弄到这幅画的?”
"Where did you get this piece?"
"好吧，别管我从哪儿弄来的，"我要在上面下注。快!”
"Well, never mind where I got it, "I want some money on it. Quick!"
“好了，好了，好了，好了，别紧张。
"Now, now, now, now, take it easy.
“一切都会好起来的。
"Everything is gonna be all right.
“进来吧。
"Just step in.
“请。
"Please.
“再远一点。”
"A little further."
砰!
Bang!
“把门锁上，我把她关在这里。”
"Lock that door while I keep her in here."
“哦!放我出去!”
"Ooh! Let me out of here!"
“你会做好的。
"You're gonna get it all right.
“喂?是的，警察局。
"Hello? Yeah, the police department.
“你好，我抓到抢劫迈耶公司的小偷了。”
"Hello, I've got the thief what robbed Meyer and Company."
辩方休息。
The defense rests.
催眠假说是一个非常有趣的假说。
The hypothesis of hypnotism is a very interesting one.
让我第一个承认吧。
Let me be the first to admit it.
但不幸的是，我不是Svengali。
But unfortunately I am no Svengali.
你们也一样，陪审团的女士们先生们。
Nor are you, ladies and gentlemen of the jury.
纽约州人民要求精神病学家凯梅茨医生提供专家证词。
The people of the state of New York will require the expert testimony of Dr. Keinmetz, the psychiatrist.
我很遗憾地告诉你，他正在佛罗里达度圣诞假期。
Whom I am sorry to say, is spending his Christmas vacation in Florida.
那你想怎么处理这件事?
Well, what do you want to do about this?
我反对，法官阁下
I object, Your Honor.
你怎么能反对他还没说过的话呢?
How can you object to something he's not yet said?
因为我知道他要说什么。
Because I know what he's going to say.
请允许，律师。
With your kind permission, Counsel.
由于辩方律师插入了一项未被证实的新内容，控方请求允许重新审理此案以便让凯梅茨博士作证。
Since the defense counsel has interjected a new element which was not testified to, the State asks permission to re-open the case for the purpose of allowing the testimony of Dr. Keinmetz.
并进一步请求延期到圣诞节假期后他就可以上班了。
And further requests that a continuance be granted till after the Christmas holidays when he will be available.
我对象!辩方已经总结完毕。
I object! The defense has summed up.
这个案子实际上已经结案了。
The case is practically closed.
反对无效。
Objection overruled.
陪审团的女士们先生们，我再次告诫你们不要互相交谈也不要与任何与本案有关的人交谈。
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury, you are again admonished not to converse among yourselves nor with anyone else connected with this trial.
在案件最终提交给你之前，你也不能对此案发表任何意见。
Nor are you to form or express any opinion concerning this case until it is finally submitted to you.
被告在交纳五千美元保释金后将继续被拘留。
The defendant will remain in custody subject to giving a $5,000 bond.
本案所有陪审员，当事人和证人请于1月3日星期二上午10点返回法庭。
All jurors, parties and witnesses in this case are instructed to return to the court Tuesday, January 3rd, at 10:00 a.m.
休庭。
Court is adjourned.
祝大家圣诞快乐。
And a very merry Christmas to you all.
那是你对我耍的肮脏把戏。
That was a dirty trick you played on me.
那就意味着又要上法庭了。
That means another day in court.
我不是为国家工作。
I'm not working for the state.
我得挣钱。
I have to earn my money.
没有幽默感。圣诞快乐，弗朗西斯。
No sense of humor. Merry Christmas, Francis.
天啊，这不是我见过的最漂亮的假反转吗。
Boy, if that wasn't the neatest fake reverse I ever saw.
是啊，他就像一匹掉进煤洞里的马一样被骗了。
Yeah, he fell for that one like a horse down a coal hole.
你把我弄得一团糟。
A fine mess you've got me into.
我以为我要出去过圣诞节了。
I thought I was gonna be out of here for Christmas.
你只要交保释金就行了。
Well, all you gotta do is post a bond.
我怎样才能交保释金?我没有钱了。
How can I post a bond? I haven't any more money.
我也不想在监狱里过圣诞节。
And I don't want to spend Christmas in jail.
请不要让他们那样做。
Please don't let them do that.
你说你没有更多的钱是什么意思?
What do you mean you haven't got any more money?
我说了些什么?听到我自己的声音?
What have I been talking for? To hear my own voice?
要不是你说了那么多，我早就走了。
If you hadn't talked so much I'd be out of here by now.
你这话是什么意思?
What do you mean by that?
催眠术。那个插科打诨太老了，都长胡子了。
Hypnotism. That gag's so old it's got whiskers.
别让他们把我关在这里过圣诞节。
Please don't let them keep me here over Christmas.
如果你出去了，你能做什么?你没有钱。
Well, what could you do if you were out? You haven't got any money.
我可以四处走动，不是吗?
I could walk around, couldn't I?
事情不会那么糟的。
It ain't gonna be as bad as all that.
你会得到一个漂亮的小房间和一个漂亮的…对，对，对。不要管积累。
You'll get a nice little room and a nice... Yeah, yeah, yeah. Nevermind the build-up.
他以为他要带我去丽兹酒店。
He thinks he's taking me to the Ritz.
祝你圣诞快乐。
I hope you have a merry Christmas.
出去的时候，让胖迈克进来。
On your way out, send Fat Mike in here.
胖麦克，那个担保人?
Fat Mike, the bondsman?
如果你认识其他胖迈克，你也可以寄给他们。
If you know any other Fat Mikes, you can send them too.
我明白了。
I get it.
你不知道，但让它过去吧。
You don't, but let it pass.
你要见我?
You want to see me?
找到匹配的了吗?
Yeah, you got a match?
一场比赛吗?当然，我找到匹配的了。
A match? Why, sure, I got a match.
我有一群。
I got a flock of them.
我,我……你知道些什么?
I, I... What do you know about that?
我发誓……我记得。我把它们给了埃尔默。
I could have swore... I remember. I gave them to Elmer.
你知道，他来找我，他说…不要紧。
You know, he come to me and he said... Never mind.
到1月3日的保释金5000元你要收多少钱?
How much will you charge for 5,000 bail till January 3rd?
他们给你栽赃了吗，伙计?
Did they pin something on you, pal?
不，不，不适合我。
No, no, it's not for me.
是给今天来过的那位年轻女士的。
It's for the young lady who was here today.
多少钱?
How much?
对你的朋友来说，不是红色沙摩卡。
Well, for a friend of yours, not a red samolka.
我不是在求你帮忙。
I'm not asking any favors.
赞成吗?这是我的荣幸。
Favors? It's a privilege.
你还住在原来的地方?
You still live in the same place?
是的。
Yeah.
你想让她多快出来?
How soon do you want her out?
马上。
Right away.
她出去了。
She's out.
谢谢。
Thanks.
我。
Me.
*今早醒来，忧郁笼罩着我的头*没有妈妈来抚慰我的伤痛…*
* Woke up this morning With the blues all around my head * Didn't have no mama To hold my aching... *
是的,先生?
Yes, sir?
大老板在吗?
Is the big boss in?
他在家，但不在家。
He's in, but he ain't home.
留着你的广播节目吧。
Save that for your radio act.
请进。
Come on in.
告诉大老板她来了，就这样。
Just tell the big boss that she's here, that's all.
谢谢胖迈克的夸奖。
With the compliments of Fat Mike.
明白了吗?
You got that?
是的，先生，迈克先生。
Yes, sir, Mr. Mike.
不是迈克先生，是胖迈克。
Not Mr. Mike, Fat Mike.
是的，先生，胖先生……迈克!
Yes, sir, Mr. Fat... Mike!
好了，宝贝，法庭上见。
Okay, toots, I'll see you in court.
请坐好吗?
Won't you sit down, please?
好吧，现在又怎么了?
Well, what's the matter now?
她在这里。
She's here.
这里是谁?
Who's here?
我不知道，先生。
I don't know, sir.
那你怎么知道她在这里?
Well, then how do you know she's here?
嗯，我看见她进来了。
Well, I see'd her come in.
你看见谁进来了吗?
You see'd who come in?
这位女士。
The lady.
你是说，公寓里有个女人?
You mean, there's a lady in the apartment?
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
你为什么让她进来?我告诉过你我没人住。
What did you let her in for? I told you I wasn't home to anybody.
我告诉了他，但他推开门，把那位女士推了进去，并说了几句恭维话。
I told him that, but he shoved the door open and pushed the lady on in with his compliments.
是谁干的?
Who did?
脂肪艾克。
Fat Ike.
胖艾克?你是说胖麦克?
Fat Ike? You mean Fat Mike?
是的，长官，他可一点都不瘦。
Yes, sir. He sure ain't no thin Ike.
你好!
How do you do?
你好。
Hello.
你在这里做什么?
What are you doing here?
我还不知道，但我有个大概的想法。
I don't know yet, but I've got a rough idea.
我很高兴你出来了……现在我要怎么做呢?
Well, I'm glad you're out and... Now what do I have to do for it?
首先，你可能会说谢谢，但如果这不符合你的计划，那就跳过它。
Well, for one thing you might say thank you, but if that doesn't fit in with your plans, just skip it.
我在这件事上的动机……苏格兰威士忌加苏打水。
My motives in this matter... Scotch and soda.
谢谢。
Thanks.
总有一天，你们中的一个男孩会以不同的方式开始其中一场戏。
One of these days, one of you boys is going to start one of these scenes differently.
我们中的一个姑娘会被吓死的。
And one of us girls is going to drop dead from surprise.
毫无疑问。现在如果你能告诉我…我想你对所有女囚犯都这么做吧?
No doubt. Now if you'll tell me... I suppose you do this with all the lady prisoners?
我,是的。我的人生就是一场漫长的狂欢。
My, yes. My life is just one long round of whoopee.
你现在的处境很好。
Well, you're in a good spot for it.
太棒了!我只需要竖起手指，我最轻微的突发奇想就能得到满足。
Wonderful! I merely have to raise my finger and my slightest whim is satisfied.
现在如果你愿意……我想如果有人说不，你就把它们放回冰箱里。
Now if you'll... And I suppose if anybody says no you just put them right back in the cooler.
这是正确的。
That's right.
听着，当法庭重新开庭的时候我会尽我所能让你在监狱里呆上很长一段时间。
Look, when court reconvenes I'm going to try my best to put you in jail for a good long time.
那是我的事。
That's my business.
但你还没有被定罪，所以我不明白你为什么不能像我们一样享受圣诞节。
But you haven't been convicted yet, so I don't see why you shouldn't enjoy Christmas like the rest of us.
所以我让迈克把你弄出来。
That's why I had Mike get you out.
把我带到这里来。
And bring me up here.
我没让他带你来这里。
I did not ask him to bring you up here.
那大猩猩为什么带我来这里?
Then why did that gorilla bring me up here?
因为他的脑子像下水道一样笨。
Because he's got a mind like a sewer.
谢谢。
Thanks.
听着，我很高兴能帮到你，但现在如果你愿意……你是说如果我不想的话，我可以留在这里吗?
Now, look, I'm very glad to have been of service to you, but now if you'll... You mean I don't have to stay here if I don't want to?
你当然不知道。
You most certainly do not.
那我就留下。
Then I'll stay.
但我不会被强迫。
But I won't be forced.
嘿，等一下。
Hey, now, wait a minute.
你知道，没有什么比方形射手更危险的了。
You know, there's nothing as dangerous as a square shooter.
如果所有的男人都像你，就不会有好女孩了。
If all men were like you there wouldn't be any nice girls left.
是的。
Yes.
好吧，所有这些都将导致一个非常有趣和深入的讨论，我现在没有时间继续讨论。
Well, all this is leading into a very interesting and deep-dish discussion, which I haven't time to pursue at the moment.
我要去短途旅行，因为要开很远的车，而且我还没吃晚饭……
I'm leaving on a little trip and as it's quite a drive and I haven't had my dinner yet...
你是说，你想让我走吗?
You mean, you want me to go?
嗯,是的。
Well, yes.
在哪里?
Where?
什么在哪里?
Where what?
好吧，毕竟，我是在去一个舒适的监狱的路上，有一日三餐和圣诞节的火鸡。
Well, after all, I was on my way to a nice comfortable jail with three meals a day and turkey for Christmas.
而现在，我……你不是住在什么地方吗?
And now, I... Don't you live someplace?
热狗!
Hot dog!
你一直住在哪儿，树上还是什么地方?
Well, where have you been living, in a tree or something?
我在酒店有个房间，但他们把我锁在外面了。
I had a room at a hotel, but they locked me out.
你欠旅馆多少钱?
And how much do you owe at the hotel?
嗯,126.40美元。
Um, $126.40.
那也解决不了你的问题，不是吗?
Well, that doesn't solve your problems, does it?
那你为什么不把我关回监狱呢。
Well, why don't you just put me back in the clink.
这会解决很多问题。
That'll solve a lot of problems.
我不确定我能不能。
Well, I'm not sure that I can.
好吧，这不是我的想法。
Well, that wasn't the idea.
你吃过晚饭了吗?
Have you had dinner?
还没有。
Not yet.
来吧，我请你吃我骗你没吃的圣诞晚餐，也许我们能想个办法。
Come on, I'll buy you that Christmas dinner I cheated you out of and maybe we can figure out something.
鲁弗斯，帮我拿外套好吗?
Rufus, get my coat, will you?
是的，萨金特先生。
Yes, sir, Mr. Sargent.
我只是给你们准备了几个三明治以防你们中途饿了。
I was just spreading y'all a few sandwiches in case you get hungry in the middle of the ride.
那你真的一点都不想让我上来吗?
You really didn't want me to come up here at all then?
很抱歉，我不知道。
I'm sorry to say I did not.
热狗!但别忘了你得去看看你妈。
Hot dog! But don't forget you gotta go see your ma.
*为你而活很轻松*生活很轻松*当你坠入爱河*而我也深陷爱河*生活中除了你什么都没有
* Living for you Is easy living * It's easy to live * When you're in love * And I'm so in love * There's nothing in life * But you *
当然，我不在的时候可以把我的公寓借给你。
Of course, I could lend you my apartment while I'm away.
听起来像在演戏，不是吗?
That sounds like a play, doesn't it?
是啊，听起来很失败。不,谢谢。
Yeah, it sounds like a flop. No, thanks.
别为我担心，我总能租一个星期左右的旅馆。
Don't worry about me, I can always chisel a hotel for a week or so.
这是个不错的俗气的主意。
That's a nice cheesy idea.
我可不想在地铁里睡觉。
Well, I'm not going to sleep in the subway.
至于假期，我想等你和我一起过完之后，我就会得到很多。
And as far as the holiday is concerned, I guess I'll get plenty of that when you get through with me.
我并不是说不愉快。你明白吗?
Not that I mean it in a disagreeable way. You understand?
我明白了。
I understand.
你的事是你的事。
Your business is your business.
不，谢谢。
No, thank you.
当然，有些人不喜欢这种生意，但总得有人干脏活。
Of course, some people wouldn't care for that kind of business but somebody has to do the dirty work.
真是太遗憾了，居然是你这么好的人。
It's just too bad it had to be somebody as nice as you.
你偷东西多久了?
How long have you been swiping things?
总是这样。
Always.
你以前被抓过吗?-你拿了你不需要的东西吗?
Did you ever get caught before? - Did you take things you didn't need?
确定。
Sure.
在美丽的事物面前，你是否突然有一种不可抗拒的冲动，想把它们拿在手里，带着它们匆匆离去?
In the presence of beautiful things, did you have the sudden irresistible urge to take them in your hands and hurry away with them?
你是说我被催眠了吗?
You mean was I hypnotized?
不，不，我是说也许你有盗窃癖。
No, no, I mean maybe you're a kleptomaniac.
不。不，他们试过了。
No. No, they tried that though.
不。你看，作为一个盗窃狂，你不能在事后卖掉任何东西，否则你就会失去业余的地位。
No. You see, to be a kleptomaniac, you can't sell any of the stuff afterwards or you lose your amateur standing.
你知道，我无法理解。
You know, I can't understand it.
一开始你认为这是遗传的，然后你发现一个七代牧师都在他身后的人。
First you think it's heredity, and then you get some guy with seven generations of clergymen behind him.
我不认为你能理解，因为你的思想是不同的。
I don't think you ever could understand because your mind is different.
你看，对与错对每个人都是一样的，但对与错却不一样。
Right or wrong is the same for everybody, you see, but the rights and the wrongs aren't the same.
就像在中国，他们吃狗肉。
Like in China, they eat dogs.
那是一堆废话。
That's a lot of piffle.
他们确实吃狗。
They do eat dogs.
不，不，我是说你的理论。
No, no, I mean your theory.
好吧，试试这样。
Well, try it like this.
假设你快饿死了，你没有食物，没有钱，也没有地方去买东西
Supposing you were starving to death, and you didn't have any food, and you didn't have any money, and you didn't have any place to get anything
市场前有一些面包。
and there were some loaves of bread out in front of a market.
现在，记住，你快饿死了，那个人转过身去了。
Now, remember, you're starving to death and the man's back was turned.
你会刷一个吗?
Would you swipe one?
我当然愿意。
You bet I would.
那是因为你很诚实。
That's because you're honest.
你知道，我会在街对面的旅馆吃一顿六道菜的晚餐，然后说我忘了带钱包。
You see, I'd have a six course dinner at the table d'hote across the street and then say I'd forgotten my purse.
明白区别了吗?
Get the difference?
是的。
Yeah.
你的方式更聪明。
Your way's smarter.
就是这样。
That's it.
我们聪明。
We're smart.
你好,杰克。你好吗？
Hello, Jack. How are you?
晚上好。
Good evening.
我想让你见见我妻子。
I want you to meet my wife.
亲爱的，这是约翰·萨金特。
My dear, this is John Sargent.
你好!你好!
How do you do? How do you do?
我是……小姐。我很抱歉。我没听清名字。
This is Miss... I'm so sorry. I didn't catch the name.
我很抱歉，杰克。我们必须快点。是的。
Well, I'm so sorry, Jack. We must hurry. Yes.
对不起，亲爱的。
I'm sorry, dear.
我没有想到这一点。
I hadn't thought of that.
哇，你真好。
Gee, you're sweet.
你从来没想错什么，是吗?
You never think of anything wrong, do you?
好吧，我们喝杯睡前酒，然后我得走了。
Well, let's have a nightcap and then I've got to get going.
几个B和B，你会让乐队演奏《我的印第安纳之家》吗?
A couple of B and B's, and will you have the band play My Indiana Home?
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
这是我欠你的火鸡大餐还有一间房和几份早餐。
Here's that turkey dinner I owe you and a room and a couple of breakfasts.
谢谢!非常感谢。
Thanks! Thanks a lot.
你不会再想和我跳舞了吧?
You wouldn't want to dance with me again, would you?
这不是在自找麻烦吗?我是说，我可能又会踩到你的脚。
Isn't that asking for trouble?... I mean, I might step on your feet again.
在这个阶段，再做几次仰卧起坐不会伤害到他们。
A couple of more crunches aren't going to hurt them at this stage.
你为什么让他们弹这首曲子?
Why did you have them play this piece?
因为那就是我要去的地方。
Because that's where I'm going.
不。你是印第安人吗?
No. Are you a Hoosier?
确定。印第安纳州沃巴什。
Sure. Wabash, Indiana.
那是沃巴什郊外的一个农场。
That is, a farm just outside of Wabash.
印第安纳州沃巴什!难怪我喜欢你。
Wabash, Indiana! No wonder I liked you.
我来自埃尔顿维尔。
I'm from Eltonville.
不!
No!
那离沃巴什只有50英里。
Why, that's only about 50 miles outside of Wabash.
是的，先生。好吧，我真倒霉!
Yes, sir. Well, I'll be darned!
想想看，我们还得来这里这样见面。
To think we had to come here and meet like this.
*我一直是一个流浪者*穿越陆地和海洋是的，我每年圣诞节都回家。
* I have always been a wanderer * Over land and sea Yes, I go home every Christmas.
你会怎么做?
You do?
我妈妈仍然经营着农场。
My mother still runs the farm.
她也很好。
She does all right, too.
养鹧鸪和波兰中国，还有…我们从来没有过这么好的东西。
Raises Partridge Wyandottes and Poland Chinas, and... We never had anything that swell.
直到最近我们才知道。
We didn't either till just lately.
你多久没回家了?
How long since you've been home?
从来没有。
Never.
为什么?
Why?
我跑了。
I ran away.
我当然不知道当时的情况，但是……不是很热。
Well, I don't know what the circumstances were, of course, but... Not so hot.
时间会解决这些问题的。
Well, time takes care of those things.
有人给你写信吗?
Folks write to you?
我父亲去世时，我收到了母亲的一封信。
I had a letter from my mother when my father died.
你妈妈还活着?
Your mother's alive?
我希望如此。
I hope so.
*闪烁的烛光*依然明亮*为我穿过梧桐树*只为我*新割的干草散发出它所有的芬芳*从我曾经漫步的田野
* The gleaming candlelight * Still shining bright * Through the sycamores for me * Just for me * The new mown hay sends all its fragrance * From the fields I used to roam
当我梦见月光时，在沃巴什河上
* When I dream about the moonlight * On the Wabash
我渴望我印第安纳州的家
* And I long for my Indiana home *
嘿，你想不想回家过圣诞节?
Say, how would you like to go home for Christmas?
我可以顺路把你放下，回来的时候再来接你。
I could drop you off on the way and pick you up on the way back.
哇。
Gee.
去年我来的时候他们在这里工作。
They were working here last year when I came through.
它说向右。
It says to the right.
就在那边!
There it is over that way!
“布莱尔一家钢厂。”
"Blairs Mills."
布莱尔一家工厂。
Blairs Mills.
布莱尔一家工厂吗?
Blairs Mills?
Blairsville。不，不是这样的。
Blairsville. No, that's not it.
这就是C-5。
Here it is, C-5.
布莱尔一家工厂。在这里。它在宾夕法尼亚州。
Blairs Mills. Here it is. It's in Pennsylvania.
我们要从那里走吗?
Are we supposed to go through there?
这里离我们要经过的地方很近。
Well, it's very close to where we were supposed to go through.
这就是我所担心的。
That's what I was afraid of.
我们最好往北走一点。
We better bear north a little.
大概有我缩略图的一半那么远。
About half as far as my thumbnail.
走到那一步告诉我一声?
Let me know when we've gone that far?
北方在哪里?往这边走。
Where is north? Up this way.
不，不，我是说从我们现在的处境来看。
No, no, I mean from where we are.
这样的。
That way.
为什么?
Why?
嗯，我们一直在往那个方向走，所以很自然，它…这样的。你确定吗?
Well, we've been going that way, so naturally, it's... That way. Are you sure?
不。
No.
看起来有点陡峭。你觉得呢?
Looks a little steep. What do you think?
这种方式!
That way!
你现在想试试哪条路?
Which way do you wanna try now?
一个看起来和另一个一样糟糕。
One looks as bad as the other.
也许我们最好放弃这一切?
Maybe we'd better just give the whole thing up?
当心!有一头大象!
Look out! There's an elephant!
什么……咦，这是一台打谷机。
What the... Why, it's a threshing machine.
我好多年没见过了。
I haven't seen one for years.
我们走不远了，对吧?
We're not getting very far, are we?
好吧，我们还撑得住。
Well, we're holding our own.
原谅我。
Excuse me.
也许我们最好先打个盹，然后再试一次?
Hey, maybe we better take a snooze and then try it again?
是的。我觉得这是个好主意。
Yes. I think that would be a lovely idea.
我可以吃掉一头牛的后腿。
I could eat the hind leg off a cow.
我可以吃牛角。
I could eat the horns.
鲁弗斯!
Rufus!
他不是很聪明，但他会做饭。
He's not very bright but he can cook.
男孩!
Boy!
现在，这比监狱好还是不好?
Now, is this better than jail or isn't it?
我几乎忘了我要进监狱了。
I'd almost forgotten I was going to be in jail.
我很抱歉。我不是那个意思。
I'm sorry. I didn't mean it that way.
这次旅行的全部目的就是忘记它。
The whole purpose of the trip was to forget it.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
鸡肉，凉拌卷心菜，莳萝泡菜，火腿，瑞士奶酪，还有一些我认不出的东西。
Chicken, coleslaw, dill pickle, ham, Swiss cheese, and something else I can't identify.
那是蜡纸。
That's the wax paper.
也不错。
Not bad, either.
我希望妈妈见到我高兴。
I hope my mother will be glad to see me.
她当然会很高兴见到你。
Of course she'll be glad to see you.
我想她会的，好吧。
Yeah, I guess she will, all right.
怎么了?
What's the matter?
看！看看谁来了。
Look! Look who's here.
早上好，老板。
Well, good morning, Bossy.
嘿，我们被包围了。
Hey, we're surrounded.
我们在哪里?
Where are we?
喂，你早餐想喝点好牛奶吗?
Say, how would you like some nice milk for breakfast?
你还知道怎么做吗?
Would you still know how?
我会吗?
Would I?
当我从事法律工作时，印第安纳州七个县失去了最好的挤奶工。
When I took up the law, Indiana lost its finest milker in seven counties.
你看着我。
You just watch me.
那么，你打算把它放在什么里面呢?
Well, what are you going to put it in?
说，这东西是……似乎没有太多的选择。
Say, this thing is... There doesn't seem to be much choice.
我能hold住。
I can hold it.
谢谢。
Thanks.
好了，老大，你待在那等我回来。
Now, Bossy, you stay there till I get around.
是的。这很可爱。
Yeah. That's pretty cute.
你待在那儿，吃早饭。
Yeah, you stay there, breakfast.
喂，我可以用什么当凳子?
Say, what can I use for a stool?
我以前总是有个凳子。
I always used to have a stool.
在这里。我来告诉你。
Here. I'll tell you.
你拿着这个，我去坐在跑步板上。
You hold this and I can go and sit on the running board.
好吧。把她的尾巴绕过来。
All right. Get her tail around.
不错,专横的。拜托，老板。结束了,老板。结束了,老板。
Nice, Bossy. Come on, Boss. Over, Boss. Over, Boss.
她喜欢别人挠她的耳朵吗?
Does she like to have her ears tickled?
是的，我想是的。好吧。
Yeah, I think so. Okay.
给，把瓶子给我。
Here, give me the bottle.
你不想让我帮你拿着吗?
Don't you want me to hold it?
不，不，我用膝盖夹着。
No, no, I'll hold it between my knees.
我以前就是这么做的。
That's the way I used to do it.
让她多呆一会儿?我试试看。
Get her around a little more? I'll try.
过来吧，老板。来吧。来吧。
Come on over, Boss. Come on. Come on.
她好像不想去!
She doesn't seem to wanna go!
也许我不坐也能做。
Maybe I can do it without sitting.
来吧，老大。我们只要一品脱。
Now, come on, Boss. All we want is about a pint.
怎么样了?好……你说什么?
How's it coming? Fine... What did you say?
我说，她想被哄。等一下，老大。
I said, she wants to be coaxed. Whoa, hold still, Boss.
好了，很好。
There, that's fine.
你说什么?
What did you say?
你有牛奶吗?
Are you getting any milk?
是的，天气很好。
Yes, it's coming fine.
嘿，别让她动。把她推回去。
Hey, don't let her move. Push her back.
我已经尽我所能了。
I'm pushing as hard as I can.
不,不喜欢。把她往那边拉。
No, don't. Pull her back that way.
够远吗?
Is that far enough?
是的，够远了!
Yes, that's far enough!
你把早餐洒了。
You spilled the breakfast.
你这么做是为了什么?现在我们得从头再来。
What did you do that for? Now we'll have to start all over again.
你欺负她。嗯…嘿，看看你的帽子!怎么了?
You pushed her around. Well... Hey, look at your hat! What's the matter?
这一点都不好笑。
that's not funny.
那是我唯一一顶和这件衣服相配的帽子。
That's the only hat I've got that matches this dress.
早上好。
Good morning.
你在我的地盘上干什么?
What are you doing on my property?
我们不知道这是你的财产。
We didn't know this was your property.
你看，我们绕道而行，然后…贴得很清楚，不是吗?
You see, we got on a detour, and... It's posted clear enough, ain't it?
每100英尺有一个标志。你不识字吗?
There's a sign every 100 feet. Can't you read?
嗯，你看，我们碰巧是在半夜到这里的。
Well, you see, we happen to have got here in the middle of the night.
是的，我注意到你拆掉了我的篱笆。
Yes, I noticed you busted down my fence.
我很乐意付钱。
I'll be glad to pay for it.
你会付出代价的，好吗?
You'll pay for it, all right.
你们纽约人以为你们可以非法侵入别人的财产，破坏他们的围栏，玩弄他们的牛，在他们的田地里过夜，和我不知道是什么…
You New Yorkers think you can trespass on people's property, break down their fences, fool around with their cattle, spend the night in their fields with I don't know what kind of a...
喂，听着，你这个肮脏的家伙……听着，你这个新来的乡巴佬…把你的语言留给法官吧!
Say, listen, you filthy-minded... Listen, you fresh hick... Save your language for the judge!
谁会逮捕我们?
Who's going to arrest us?
你被捕了。
You're under arrest now.
你的搜查令或警徽呢?
Well, where's your warrant or your badge of office?
别装可爱!
Don't get cute!
我是美国公民，你被捕了。
I'm a citizen of the United States, and you're under arrest.
如果你不这么认为，那就试着离开。
And if you think you ain't, just try to get away.
他能做到吗?
Can he do that?
不幸的是，他可以。
Unfortunately, he can.
我们怎么办，走路吗?我们会骑。
What'll we do, walk? We'll ride.
打开那个隆隆作响的座位。
Open that rumble seat.
你自己打开吧。
Open it yourself.
请把你的手帕给我好吗?
May I have your handkerchief, please?
谢谢你！
Thank you.
在这里。
Right here.
不要说出你的真名。
Don't give your right name.
这是个好主意。也不要给我你的。
That's a good idea. Don't give yours, either.
我从来没有。
I never do.
我今天早上给他们买的蛋糕还好吗?
Did I get them cakes all right this morning?
很好。
Fine.
看起来是生意，克莱德。
Looks like business, Clyde.
我敢说，如果这不是奉子成婚的话…不，那是汉克。他可能有几个非法侵入者。
Well, I declare if that ain't a shotgun wedding... No, that's Hank. He's probably got a couple of trespassers.
有了这条新弯路，他总是能抓到他们。
With that new detour, he gets 'em all the time.
真可惜他不能等到别人吃完早饭再说。
Well, it's a pity he couldn't wait till a body's had his breakfast.
我要见治安法官。
I want to see the Justice of the Peace.
去吧!
Go on!
有点早，不是吗?
Kinda early, ain't you?
早上好，法官阁下。
Good morning, Your Honor.
这里似乎有点小误会。
There seems to have been a little misunderstanding here all around.
这位先生在他的田地里发现了我的车，自然而然地得出结论……什么罪名，汉克?
This gentleman here found my car in his field and naturally he came to the conclusion that... What's the charge, Hank?
擅闯张贴的财产，肆意破坏围栏，以及轻微盗窃罪。
Trespassing on posted property, wanton destruction of a fence, and petty larceny.
这不是……他们偷了什么?
That's not... What'd they steal?
他们在给我的一头奶牛挤奶时被我抓住了。
They was milking one of my cows when I caught 'em.
装在这么大的保温瓶里!
In a little thermos bottle that big!
没人问你什么，小姑娘。
Nobody asked you anything, young woman.
轮到你的时候，你想说什么就说什么。
When it comes your turn, you can talk all you like.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
玛丽·史密斯。
Mary Smith.
你住在哪里?
Where do you live?
咆哮瀑布，俄亥俄州。
Roaring Falls, Ohio.
职业?
Occupation?
泡沫的舞者。
Bubble dancer.
泡泡舞者，你知道的。
Bubble dancer, you know.
不管那是什么!
Whatever that is!
泡沫的舞者。
Bubble dancer.
好吧。你叫什么名字?
All right. What's your name?
亨利·沃兹沃思·朗费罗。
Henry Wadsworth Longfellow.
纽约，纽约。
New York, New York.
亨利·沃兹沃思·朗费罗。
Henry Wadsworth Longfellow.
纽约。
New York.
职业?
Occupation?
Steamfitter。
Steamfitter.
好吧。你是认罪还是不认罪?
All right. Do you plead guilty or not guilty?
法官大人，我对法律程序有些熟悉，因为我曾经考虑过法律。
May it please Your Honor, I am somewhat familiar with legal procedure, having at one time contemplated the law.
那你就不该违法。
Then you shouldn't have broken the law.
这是对事实的无知，法官阁下。
It was an ignorance of the fact, Your Honor.
无知不是借口。
Ignorance is no excuse.
我知道这一点，我也知道非本州居民提出的"无罪抗辩"意味着什么。
I'm aware of that, and I'm also aware of what a plea of "not guilty" means when made by non-residents of the State.
还没结婚呢。
Ain't even married.
我不知道你说的"结婚"是什么意思
I don't know what you mean by "even married."
你说“甚至结婚了”，好像结婚是人们最不可能的事，是一种微不足道的安排!
You say "even married" as though married was the least people could be, some minor, unimportant arrangement!
我呼吁您的骑士精神，法官大人。
I appeal to your sense of chivalry, Your Honor.
我猜你是个已婚男人，开门的那位迷人的女士是你的……在我的地盘过夜，从外地来的。
I take it you're a married man and that the charming lady who opened the door was your... Spent the night in my field, from out of the state.
我的博学的对手，我是说那个拿着猎枪的暴徒，试图在这个案件中注入一种……你是认罪还是不认罪?
My learned opponent here, I mean that thug with the shotgun, is trying to inject into this case an element of... Do you plead guilty or not guilty?
什么?你一定觉得有点好笑……非法侵入，破坏私有财产，以及小偷小摸。
To what? It must feel kinda funny to you... To trespass, destruction of private property, and petty larceny.
你将就什么?
What'll you settle for?
我将就什么呢?
What'll I settle for?
你学法律的时候听说过藐视法庭罪吗?
Did you ever hear of contempt of court while you were studying the law?
我想我还是把你交给警察然后送你去县政府吧!
I think I'll just remand you to the constable and send you over to the county seat!
现在，等一下……等等,什么!
Now, wait a minute... Wait, nothing!
我本想给你一个公平的审判，但当男人像你一样开车把女孩越过州界，这件事就值得调查了。
I was trying to give you a fair trial, but when men drive girls over the state line as you did, the matter's worth investigating.
此外，当他们给亨利·沃兹沃思·朗费罗起有趣的名字时。
Also, when they give funny names like Henry Wadsworth Longfellow.
你可能认为你在和乡巴佬打交道，我要给你机会……
You may think you're dealing with rubes and I'm going to give you the opportunity...
这是什么?
What is it?
得到一些东西!
Get something!
原谅我。怎么了?
Pardon me. What's the matter?
喝点水。办公室着火了。
Get some water. The office is on fire.
水!水!水!
Water! Water! Water!
这只是一个废纸篓。来吧!
It's only a wastebasket. Come on!
不要紧。
Never mind.
在那里。
There.
那只丁当怎么着火了…我们找到了。
How the ding dang that ever caught on fire... We've got it.
他们去哪了?
Well, where'd they go?
好吧，我真倒霉!
Well, I'll be god-darned!
嘿!
Hey!
汉克，你会打破我的窗户的。
Hank, you'll break my window.
别这么做，汉克。汉克，你会打破窗户的。
Don't do it, Hank. Hank, you'll break the window.
在那里!
There!
你是傻瓜吗?着火了!
Are you a loon? There's the fire!
好吧，就是这样。在回去的路上，我想我们得绕道加拿大了。
Well, that's that. On the way back, I suppose we'll have to duck around through Canada.
我想那样会更好。
I guess that would be better.
你一定觉得当逃犯很好笑吧。
It must feel kind of funny to you to be a fugitive from justice.
很有趣。
Very funny.
你知道吗，穿过宾夕法尼亚，我一直想弄清楚那场火是怎么开始的。
You know, all the way across Pennsylvania, I've been trying to figure out how that fire got started.
没有人吸烟。
Nobody was smoking.
我是。
I was.
你是吗?
You were?
你往篮子里扔东西了吗?
Did you throw anything in that basket?
除了火柴什么都没有。
Nothing but a match.
一根点燃的火柴?
A lighted match?
我想那里面一定有生命。
I guess there must have been some life in it.
你是故意扔进去的吗?
Did you throw it in there on purpose?
我的目标不是痰盂。
Well, I wasn't aiming for the spittoon.
我想你知道那叫纵火吧。
I suppose you know that's called arson.
不!
No!
我以为那是你咬人的时候。
I thought that was when you bit somebody.
“咬人!”
"Bit somebody!"
总比进监狱好，不是吗?
Well, it's better than going to jail, isn't it?
我告诉过你我的思维方式不一样。
I told you my mind worked differently.
你知不知道那房子可能在一英里高的地方着火了?
Do you realize that house is probably in flames a mile high?
我希望是这样。我也是。
I hope it is. Well, so do I.
但这和这个案子的道德有什么关系呢?
But what's that got to do with the morals of the case?
这跟道德有什么关系?
What have morals got to do with it?
你把我当妹妹看待。
You've treated me like your sister.
我们到了。
Here we are.
它没有太大变化。
It hasn't changed much.
新药店。
New drugstore.
是的，他们会在一夜之间潜入。
Yeah, they creep in overnight.
那是我第一次参加舞会的地方。
That's where I went to my first dance.
我第一次参加舞会是在消防站。
I went to my first dance in a firehouse.
我也去过消防站。
I've been to the firehouse, too.
我要一直往前走吗?
Do I keep ongoing straight ahead?
不，你在下一个路口左转。
No, you turn left at the next corner.
在轨道的另一边大约一英里。
It's about a mile the other side of the tracks.
我开始害怕了。
I'm getting scared.
现在,现在。
Now, now.
请。让我们等到……她可能都不住在这里了。
Please. Let's wait till... She might not even live here anymore.
看在上帝的份上，别紧张。
Now, don't be nervous, for heaven's sake.
你愿意和我一起进去吗?
Will you go in with me?
当然，我和你一起进去。来吧。
Sure, I'll go in with you. Come on.
看到那棵树了吗?
See that tree?
我12岁的时候摔了下来。
I fell out of it when I was 12.
从那个分支开始。
From that branch right there.
我是个糟糕的假小子。
I was a terrible tomboy.
如果我是个男人，我就会跑到海里去。
If I'd been a man, I would have run away to sea.
我的头着地了。
I landed on my head.
是吗?这比催眠更搞笑。
Yeah? That's a better gag than hypnotism.
你的律师为什么不用这个?
Why didn't your lawyer use that?
我不知道。
I don't know.
你应该请我当你的律师。
You should have had me for your lawyer.
好了，我们到了。
Well, here we are.
来吧，微笑。
Come on now, smile.
我不是故意敲门那么大声的。
I didn't mean to knock so loud.
怎么，听起来像米奇。
Why, that sounds like Mickey.
不过我不这么认为，他会……闭嘴!
I don't suppose it is though, he'd be... Shut up!
有人要来了。
Somebody's coming.
天啊，你真好。
Gee, you've been sweet.
是吗?
Yes?
我非常抱歉。
I'm terribly sorry.
马龙太太不住这儿了吗?
Doesn't Mrs. Malone live here anymore?
我想你是说我妻子。
I guess you mean my wife.
马!外面有人想见你。
Ma! Somebody out there wants to see you.
圣诞快乐，妈妈。
Merry Christmas, Mama.
进来。
Come in.
嗯，这位是……萨金特。萨金特。
Um, this is Mr... Sargent. Sargent.
你好!
How do you do?
坐下来。
Sit down.
你看起来很好，妈妈。
You're looking fine, Mama.
你来这儿干什么?你想要什么?
What'd you come here for? What do you want?
我什么都不要，妈妈。
I don't want anything, Mama.
那天刚好是圣诞节，萨金特先生碰巧在开车……你知道，我就住在沃巴什附近，我知道你会很乐意……所以他把我带来了。
It was just Christmas, and Mr. Sargent happened to be driving... You see, I live just outside of Wabash, and I knew you'd be glad to... So he brought me with him.
高兴吗?我为什么要高兴呢?
Glad? Why should I be glad?
她走的那天，我说:“总算摆脱了那些垃圾。”
"Good riddance to bad rubbish," I said the day she left.
求你了,妈妈。萨金特……就像她的父亲一样。
Please, Mama. Mr. Sargent... Just like her father, she is.
她总是对严肃的事情发笑。
Always laughing at serious things, she was.
她从不听话，直到她像我说的那样偷东西。
Never doing what she was told, till she winds up stealing, as I always said she would.
偷了我辛辛苦苦存起来的任务经费。
Stealing my mission money that I put by with the sweat of my brow.
我没有偷。
I didn't steal it.
我跟你说过一千遍了，我只是借的。
I've told you a thousand times I only borrowed it.
我本来打算用我赚的钱还你的。
I was going to pay you back out of what I'd earn.
但你没有还我钱，对吧?
But you didn't pay me back, did you?
你从没还过我钱，也没还过别人钱。
And you never paid me back, and you never paid anybody else back.
你当着全镇人的面说我是小偷，我怎么能这么做?
How could I after you called me a thief in front of the whole town?
你觉得之后还有人会让我为他们工作吗?
Do you think anybody'd let me work for them after that?
我们在这里配不上她，一个体面的家，一个勤劳的母亲和一个骗子的女儿。
We weren't good enough for her here, a decent home and a hardworking mother with a crook for a daughter.
我不想催你，但我们还有50英里要走。
I don't want to rush you, but we've still got 50 miles to go.
你不觉得我们该走了吗?
Don't you think we'd better be on our way?
谢谢。
Thanks.
再见,妈妈。
Goodbye, Mama.
很高兴见到你，夫人。这个名字与你无关。
It's been very interesting meeting you, Mrs... The name doesn't concern you.
当然不是。
It certainly does not.
来吧，现在。
Come on, now.
事情没那么糟。
It isn't as bad as that.
我忘了那个女人是多么恨我，而我是多么恨她。
I'd forgotten how much that woman hates me, and how much I hate her.
这么说太可怕了，不是吗?
That's a terrible thing to say, isn't it?
从我小时候起，她总是对的，而我总是错的。
Ever since I was little, she was always so right and I was always so wrong.
她总是那么好，而我总是那么坏。她……
She was always so good and I was always so bad. She...
谢谢你把我救出来。
Thank you for getting me out.
我愿意待在任何地方，只是不要在这里，不要离她这么近!
I'll stay anywhere, only not here, not so close to her!
嘿。
Hey.
我真希望从树上掉下来的时候摔断了脖子。
I wish I'd broken my neck when I fell out of that tree.
现在想这个有点晚了，不是吗?
It's a little late to think about that now, isn't it?
你不会让我留在埃尔顿维尔吧?不，我不会的。
You won't make me stay in Eltonville? No, I won't.
你能给我另找个房间吗?
You'll find me a room someplace else?
我会的。
I will.
任何旧垃圾场都可以。
Any old dump will do.
这就是你要得到的。
That's just what you're gonna get.
只有一扇窗户，床垫是用石头填的，还有一幅画，画的是你这辈子见过的最对眼的老头。
It's only got one window, and the mattress is stuffed with rocks, and there's a painting of the cross-eyedest old guy you ever saw in your life.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know?
我怎么知道是什么?我祖父是斗鸡眼?
How do I know what? That my grandfather was cross-eyed?
你是说你…你要带我回家?
You mean you're... You're taking me home with you?
当然，为什么不呢?
Sure, why not?
嘿!现在怎么办呢?
Hey! Now what?
你想把火放在哪里，萨金特夫人?
Where do you want that fire laid, Mrs. Sargent?
天哪，威利!
Land sakes, Willie!
二楼只有一个壁炉。
There's only one fireplace on the second floor.
你还没放好火吗?
Haven't you laid that fire yet?
不。他们让我削土豆。
No. They had me peeling potatoes.
艾米，我觉得饼干烧焦了!
Emmy, I think those cookies are burning!
土地的缘故!
Land sakes!
露西·萨金特，饼干没烧焦!
Lucy Sargent, those cookies are not burning!
我敢说，只要杰克一回家，你的样子就足以让人发疯了。
I declare it's enough to drive a body crazy the way you carry on when Jack comes home.
我还没烧过东西，而且…
I've never burned anything yet, and it's...
在那里。
There.
我是该现在生火呢，萨金特太太，还是等他来?
Should I light the fire now, Mrs. Sargent, or wait till he gets here?
威利，房间看起来冷吗?
Does the room seem chilly, Willie?
不，看起来不冷，威利…我觉得很冷，但是，这周围的人整天把我折腾得精疲力尽，我怀疑即使在……冰池。
No, it don't seem chilly Willie... Chilly to me, but, then the way everybody around this place has been running me ragged all day long, I doubt if I'd be chilly even in a... Ice pond.
谢谢你，女士。
Thank you, ma'am.
听着，威利·西姆斯，如果你再抱怨，我宣布我要……我不知道该怎么办了。
Now, see here, Willie Sims, if you don't stop complaining, I declare I'll... Well, I don't know what I'll do.
在这里，你得到了一个可爱的家，除了几头牛和几只鸡…和猪。
Here you are getting a lovely home with nothing but a few cows and chickens to... And pigs.
几头猪是什么?
What are a few pigs?
和骡子。
And mules.
他们不需要任何照顾。
They don't need any care.
而不是感激……还有公牛。
And instead of being grateful... And the bull.
好吧，公牛。但即便如此……兔子。
All right, the bull. But even so... Rabbits.
兔子。
Rabbits.
和鸭子。
And ducks.
和山羊。
And goats.
艾米，他来了!
Emmy, he's here!
威利，下去把门打开，好吗?
Willie, go down and open the door, will you?
别忘了还有火!威利，把他的包拿进来。
And don't forget the fire! Willie, bring in his bags.
火。
The fire.
来，把火柴给我，我自己来生火。
Here, give me the matches and I'll light the fire myself.
但是你……比赛!比赛!
But you... The matches! The matches!
袋。
The bags.
在那里!
There!
天啊!
Gosh!
铁杉。
Hemlock.
他来了!
Here he is!
艾米，快点。来吧!
Emmy, hurry up. Come on!
天哪，他有一辆新车!
Boy, he's got a new car!
他有一辆新车!
He's got a new car!
杰克!我简直等不及了!
Jack! I could hardly wait!
我太高兴了!你好,妈妈。
I'm so glad! Hello, Mother.
我的男孩!我的男孩!你好吗，妈妈?
My boy! My boy! How are you, Mother?
你好，艾美阿姨。
Hello, Aunt Emmy.
约翰·萨金特!
John Sargent!
我很高兴你在这里。
I declare I'm glad you're here.
只要不让你母亲失去理智就好。
If only to keep your mother from taking leave of her senses.
上周，这所房子一直…天啊。
For the last week, this house has been... Gosh.
你好,威利。还有女孩追你吗?
Hiya, Willie. Girls still chasing you?
你为什么迟到了?我们期待你6点来。
Why are you late? We expected you at 6:00.
你没出事故吧?
You didn't have an accident, did you?
嗯,没有。你看到…那是谁?
Well, no. You see... Who's that?
妈妈，艾玛阿姨，威利，这是来和我们一起过圣诞节的李利安德小姐。
Mother, Aunt Emma, Willie, this is Miss Lee Leander who's come to spend Christmas with us.
你好。
Hello.
我希望不会给你添太多麻烦。
I hope I won't be too much trouble.
麻烦吗?哎呀，上帝保佑你，孩子，你在这儿真是太高兴了。
Trouble? Why, bless you, child, it's a joy to have you here.
你应该发个电报，约翰·萨金特。
You might have sent a telegram, John Sargent.
自从你克拉拉阿姨来做罐头后爷爷的房间就没打扫过。
Grandpa's room hasn't been cleaned since your Aunt Clara was here for canning.
嘿，露西·萨金特，不是这样的!
Why, Lucy Sargent, that's not so!
怎么了，威利上周还在那呢。
Why, I had Willie in there just last week.
天啊!
Gosh!
它像口哨一样干净。
It's as clean as a whistle.
我对此表示怀疑。走吧，亲爱的。
Well, I doubt it. Come along, my dear.
你一定冻坏了，我们就像两只老母鸡一样站在这儿。
You must be freezing, and here we are standing like a couple of old hens.
你把饼干忘在烤箱里了吗?
Did you forget the cookies in the oven?
仁慈的天堂!
Merciful heavens!
小心点，艾米。
Be careful, Emmy.
来吧，亲爱的。
Come on, dear.
男孩!
Boy!
怎么啦？
What?
她不是很漂亮吗?
Ain't she a peach-a-rino?
我只能说热狗!
All I can say is hot dog!
给，拿着这些。
Here, take these.
也许我错了，但我的艾玛阿姨可能是世界上第二好的厨师。
You know, I may be wrong, but my Aunt Emma is probably the second best cook in the world.
你真会说话，杰克。
How you talk, Jack.
谁是第一名?
Who's the first best?
在那里。那个房间还远不够干净，李，但还过得去。
There. That room is still far from clean, Lee, but it's passable.
嗯，以前还过得去。
Well, it was pretty passable before.
嗯，现在很完美了。
Well, it's perfect now.
她为什么让你这么做?
Why did she make you do that?
威利本来可以轻而易举地做到的。
Why, Willie could have done them so easily.
威利。当然,威利。
Willie. Sure, Willie.
我喜欢做这些。我住过旅馆和……地方太久了，我没有像我想的那样经常在房子周围呆着。
I like doing them. I've lived in hotels and... Places so long, I haven't been around a house as much as I'd like to.
你父母都死了?
Your folks dead?
威利!
Willie!
我父亲死了。我母亲再婚了。
My father's dead. My mother's remarried.
我总是说这对孩子们来说太难了。
I always say that's so hard on children.
不管新父母有多好，都是不一样的。
No matter how nice the new parent is, it just isn't the same.
我看不出这有什么区别。
I don't see why that should make the slightest difference.
艾米!
Emmy!
嗯，我不知道。
Well, I don't.
好吧，来吧，大家，我们现在都到客厅去，听杰克弹钢琴。
Well, come on, everybody, let's all go in the parlor now and we'll listen to Jack play the piano.
我曾经上过价值14美元的钢琴课，他们永远不会忘记。
I took $14 worth of piano lessons once, and they've never forgotten it.
我会唱歌。
I can sing.
给你。
Here you are.
别全吃了。
Now, don't eat it all.
我们要把它系在圣诞树上。
We're going to string it for the Christmas tree.
Mi, Mi, Mi, Mi *
* Mi, mi, mi, mi *
李，亲爱的，你坐在这儿。
Lee, dear, you sit over here.
和艾美奖。
And Emmy.
你坐在这里。
You sit over here.
好吧。把火柴给我，威利。
All right. Give me the matches, Willie.
在你听到这个之前，你什么都没听到。
Until you've heard this, you've heard nothing.
考虑到他手的大小，他真的打得很好。
He really plays very well when you consider the size of his hands.
把爆米花给我，威利。
Bring me the popcorn, Willie.
演奏斯瓦尼河，杰克。
Play Swanee River, Jack.
斯旺尼河吗?然后唱出来。
Swanee River? And sing it.
都准备好了吗?
All ready?
*沿着斯旺尼河向下*遥远，遥远
* Way down upon the Swanee River * Far, far away
*那里是我的心永远转动的地方*那里是老人们停留的地方
* There's where my heart is turning ever * There's where the old folks stay
可爱吗?
Cute, too?
*上上下下的整个创造物*悲伤的我漫游
* All up and down the whole creation * Sadly I roam
*仍然怀念旧的创造*怀念家里的老人们*
* Still longing for the old creation * And for the old folks at home *
就是这样。
That's that.
再弹一个曲子，杰克!
Play one more piece now, Jack!
快出来!
Get out of there!
不，先生，要等到明年。
No, sir, not till next year.
请再做一次。
Please do just one more.
现在，来吧。我不知道了。
Now, come on. I don't know anymore.
是的，你知道我非常喜欢的圣诞颂歌。
Yes, you know the Christmas carol that I like so much.
妈妈，我们来了客人。
Mother, we've got a guest.
她也想听你说。你不会吗，李?
Well, she'd like to hear it, too. Wouldn't you, Lee?
我会弹一首曲子。我过去常在一毛钱店玩。
I can play a piece. I used to play in the ten-cent store.
那太好了。
That'd be nice.
我会唱《完美一天的结束》
I can sing The End of a Perfect Day.
威利!
Willie!
嗯，我可以。
Well, I can.
好吧，每个人都可以。
Well, so can everybody else.
来吧，威利，唱吧!
Come on, Willie, sing it!
好吧。
All right.
*当你来到*完美的一天结束*你独自坐着思考
* When you come * To the end of a perfect day * And you sit alone with your thought
*当钟声响起时*伴着欢快的颂歌*为这一天带来的欢乐
* While the chimes ring out * With a carol gay * For the joy * That the day has brought
*你认为*完美一天的结束*对一颗疲惫的心意味着什么?
* Do you think * What the end of a perfect day * Can mean to a tired heart?
*当夕阳西下*伴着燃烧的光芒*亲爱的朋友们*不得不分离*
* When the sun goes down * With a flaming ray * And the dear friends * Have to part *
天啊，孩子!你想得肺炎吗?
Land sakes, child! You want to catch pneumonia?
在那里!
There!
我想你最好也带一个热水瓶。
And I think you'd better have a hot water bottle, too.
你看起来有点憔悴。
You look a little peaked.
我像马一样强壮。
I'm as strong as a horse.
在这种天气里，很多马都有毛毛。
Well, many a horse has frizz in this weather.
妈妈吗?是的,亲爱的。
Mother? Yes, dear.
我不知道该不该告诉你，但我不想在你不知道她是谁的情况下把她带到你家里。
I don't know whether I should tell you this or not, but I don't like to bring somebody under your roof without your knowing exactly who she is.
我想我能猜到。
I think I can guess.
怎么啦？不，一点也不。
What? No, not at all.
她甚至都不是我的朋友。
She isn't even a friend of mine.
我觉得她很迷人。
Why, I think she's charming.
她让我想起了你父亲的表妹温妮弗雷德，她在第二个孩子出生时就去世了。
She reminds me of your father's cousin Winifred, who died when her second was born.
她是一个甜美可爱的人。
She was a sweet, lovely thing.
我刚跟你艾米阿姨说我觉得…是的，她很迷人，母亲，但不幸的是她是个骗子。
I was just telling your Aunt Emmy that I thought that... Yes, she is charming, Mother, but unfortunately she's a crook.
等我们回到纽约，我要把她送进监狱。
When we get back to New York, I'm going to try to put her in jail.
但与此同时，她没有地方过圣诞节，所以…可怜的小羊羔!
But in the meantime, she didn't have any place to spend Christmas, so... The poor lamb!
约翰，你不会这么做的。
John, why, you'll do no such thing.
那个女孩非常诚实。
That girl's as honest as all outdoors.
为什么，我一看她的脸就知道了。
Why, I can tell by just looking at her face.
如果她真的吃了什么，我敢肯定那完全是她的错。
If she did take anything, I'm sure it was entirely by mistake.
她可能有疑病症。
She's probably a hypochondriac.
也许是吧。
She might be, at that.
她什么都没拿吗?
She didn't really take anything?
你只是在开玩笑，对吧?
You're just making a bad joke, aren't you?
不,妈妈。恐怕这都不是她的初犯。
No, Mother. I'm afraid it's not even her first offense.
但这并不意味着她不快乐，不孤独，不像我们其他人一样是人。
But that doesn't mean that she wasn't unhappy and lonely, and a human being like the rest of us.
可怜的家伙!
The poor thing!
她小时候可能没有得到足够的爱。
She probably didn't get enough love as a child.
你还记得有多糟糕吗?你也不算太坏，但你还记得你拿了我买鸡蛋的钱，我打算用它买件新裙子，
Do you remember how bad... Well, you weren't really bad, but do you remember when you took my egg money I was going to buy a new dress with,
当你明白了之后，你又如何努力去偿还?
and then how hard you worked to pay it back when you did understand?
你让我明白了。
You made me understand.
不,亲爱的。是爱让你明白。
No, dear. It was love that made you understand.
我希望她和我们在这里过得愉快。
I hope she's going to enjoy her stay here with us.
我们想让她快乐和舒适……看到了吗?
We want to make her happy and comfortable... See that?
皮革也很好。
It's good leather, too.
杰克!
Jack!
你去年圣诞节给我的那瓶酒我还没喝呢!
Why, I haven't even started that bottle you gave me last Christmas!
“狂喜时刻!”
"Hour Of Ecstasy!"
这和你去年圣诞节送她的一样。
That's the same kind you gave her last Christmas.
它是什么?他们告诉我那是最新的!
It is? They told me that was the latest!
嗯，我喜欢它!
Well, I love it!
是不是很漂亮?
Isn't that pretty?
这也是最新的消息，艾米阿姨。
That's the latest too, Aunt Emmy.
怎么，杰克·萨金特，你应该为自己感到羞耻!
Why, Jack Sargent, you ought to be ashamed of yourself!
我从来没有……威利!威利，还有一件事。
I never... Willie! Willie, here's something else.
男孩!
Boy!
哎呀，我喜欢圣诞节!
Gee, I love Christmas!
这是最新消息，威利。
That's the latest, Willie.
不，你穿反了。
No, you've got it on backwards.
不不，威利，这边走。
No, no, Willie, this way.
这是正确的。那条路?
That's right. That way?
只是你要用它来模仿。
Only you've got to yodel with it.
我待会再练习。
I'll practice up on that later.
天啊，太时髦了!找一面镜子。
Boy, is it snazzy! Find a mirror.
把我的东西都收拾好。亲爱的!
Get all my stuff together. Dear!
“妈妈寄来的杰克。”
"Jack from Mother,"
是的。
Yes.
有衣服穿吗?
Something to wear?
你等着瞧吧。
You wait and see.
一件毛衣吗?
A sweater?
你自己织的吗?
Did you knit it yourself?
谢谢,妈妈。这是膨胀。
Thanks, Mother. That's swell.
你喜欢这个颜色吗?确定。
You like the color? Sure.
好吧，我希望它合适。
Well, I hope it fits.
它会健康。
It'll fit.
“艾玛阿姨给杰克。”
"To Jack from Aunt Emma."
等不及要看了。
Can't wait to see it.
袜子呢?
Well, socks?
不是很高档，但能让你的脚暖和。
Not so fancy, but they'll keep your feet warm.
你觉得合身吗?
Do you think they'll fit?
嗯，我不知道。
Well, I don't know.
谢谢你，艾美阿姨。
Thanks, Aunt Emmy.
很幸运吗?
Well, pretty lucky?
你的赌注。
You bet.
对现在的情况我很抱歉。如果……那边还有一些其他的包裹。看看是给谁的。
Say, I'm sorry about the present situation. If... There's some other packages over there. See who they're for.
“李……”
"To Lee..."
好吧，我猜圣诞老人总是靠得住的。
Well, I guess you can always depend on Santa Claus.
圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
不，你不该费这么大的劲。
No, you shouldn't have gone to all this trouble.
快点，现在就把它们打开。
Come on, open them up right now.
谢谢你！它太漂亮了。
Thank you. It's so pretty.
这真的没什么。
It's really nothing at all.
只是用我多年来积累的一些废料和东西做的。
Just made from some scraps and things that I've accumulated through the years.
嗯，它很可爱。
Well, it's lovely.!
阿姨艾玛?
Aunt Emma?
虽然不怎么花哨，但对于一个老处女来说，在寒冷的夜晚也很不错!
Not so fancy, but they're grand on a cold night, for a spinster lady!
你真是太好了!
It's awfully sweet of you!
威利，谁寄来的?不。
Who's that from, Willie? No.
为什么，你这个笨蛋!
Why, you dunce!
你什么都不记得了吗?
Can't you remember anything?
狂喜时刻!
Hour Of Ecstasy!
是的，这是最新的消息。
Yeah, that's the latest.
这是我给你的，对吧?
That's the one I gave you, right?
谢谢你！
Thank you!
你们都太好了。
You're all much too kind.
我从来没见过这么体贴的人，而且……哎呀，亲爱的，这根本没什么。
I've never met anyone so thoughtful and so... Why, my dear, it's nothing at all.
为什么，我们就是喜欢这样做。我们很高兴你能住在这里，我们非常希望你能在这里过得愉快。
Why, we just love doing it. We're happy to have you here, and we're so anxious for you to enjoy your stay.
你确实没有太多事情可做，所以你只能充分利用它。
There really isn't very much for you to do, so you'll just have to make the best of it.
今晚有几个朋友要来，我们要去抢苹果，然后明天年轻人要在雪地里寻宝，后天我们要去玩太妃糖游戏。
Tonight, a few friends are coming in, we're going to bob for apples, and then tomorrow the young people are going to have a treasure hunt in the snow, and the next day we have a taffy pull.
那会把房子弄脏吗。
And will that gum up the house.
天啊!嘘!
Gosh! Shh!
这不会是一排大头针。
It won't amount to a row of pins.
第二天我们会在教堂举行义卖和慈善自助餐。
And the day after that we have the rummage sale and the charity buffet at the church.
像你这样漂亮的姑娘应该能帮上大忙。
A pretty girl like you ought to be a big help.
为什么，这些人太紧了，我们几乎要抠他们的口袋……
Why, the men are so tight, we almost have to pick their pock...
好吧，我会尽力的。
Well, I'll do my best.
我的专长就是骗他们!
My specialty's shortchanging 'em!
艾美夫人!
MRS. - Emmy!
然后我们休息一天，再过一天就是除夕。
And then we rest up for a day, and the day after that is New Year's Eve.
今年我们要跳老式的谷仓舞就像乡巴佬一样。
This year we're going to have an old-fashioned barn dance like the hicks we're supposed to be.
这就是全部。
And that's all there is.
农民的妻子不再死于无聊，而是死于心力衰竭。
Farmers' wives don't die of boredom anymore, they die of heart failure.
你认为它们被爆了吗?
Do you suppose they're popped?
我肯定它们爆了。
I'm positive they've popped.
天啊，我真希望我能那么确定。
Gee, I wish I could be that sure.
等我告诉你秘密，你就会是了。
You will be when I've told you the secret.
但你绝不能让它从家里传出去。
But you must never let it out of the family.
你看到…
You see...
不，你确定吗?是的。
No, are you sure? Yes.
自己去找吧。
Look for yourself.
早上好。
Good morning.
早上好。吃点早餐怎么样?
Good morning. How's about some breakfast?
天哪，弹窗!
Holy smoke, popovers!
而且完全是她自己做的。
And she made them entirely by herself.
她做吗?好吧，带他们进来。
She did? Well, bring 'em in.
你为什么要告诉他那个?
What did you tell him that for?
难道你不知道通往男人心的捷径是通过他的胃吗?
Don't you know the shortcut to a man's heart's through his gizzard?
来，趁热吃吧。
Here, take 'em in while they're hot.
给你。
There you are.
走吧，快点!
Go on, hurry up!
我都不知道你会做饭。
Say, I didn't know you could cook.
这些不是我做的。她只是说我喜欢。
I didn't make these. She just said I did.
她为什么这么说?
Why'd she say that?
因为她教会了我怎么做。但我……我猜她觉得如果你觉得我知道怎么做，为什么，事情就会进展得更快。
Because she's taught me how. But I... Well, I guess she thought if you thought I knew how, why, that would make everything go faster.
让什么走得更快?
Make what go faster?
她以为你带我来这里是因为你爱上我了。
You see, she thinks you brought me out here because you're in love with me.
很有趣，不是吗?是的。
Funny, isn't it? Yeah.
如果你认为我做不出这么好吃的弹窗，那你就疯了!
Well, if you think I couldn't make a popover as good as that, you're nuts!
法官，你就不能在我这桌买东西吗?
Judge, won't you buy something at my table?
我马上就回来。请。
I'll be back in just a minute. Please.
等一下，我马上回来。
Now, just a minute, I'll be back.
法官，你一定要买这块桌布。
Judge, you just must buy this tablecloth.
好的，好的，我马上就回来。
Yes, yes, I'll be back in just a minute.
等一下。我马上回来。
Just a minute. I'll be back.
法官，买个漂亮的相框怎么样?
Judge, how about a nice picture frame?
我在找我的帽子，一顶丝绸帽子。
I'm looking for my hat, a silk hat.
我妻子送来的。
My wife sent it down here.
镇上最富有，最吝啬的人。别这样，艾米。
Richest, tightest man in town. Come on, Emmy.
法官。是吗?
Judge. Yes?
艾玛阿姨，记下一个犰狳篮子，7美元的。
Aunt Emma, mark down one armadillo basket, the $7 size.
好吧。现在，等一下!
All right. Now, just a minute!
没关系。我告诉你该怎么做。
That's all right. I'll tell you what you do.
亲爱的小姐，我们以6美元的价格卖给你，你还可以亲亲艾玛阿姨。
My dear miss. We'll let you have it for $6 and you can kiss Aunt Emma in the bargain.
"吻艾玛阿姨"?这太过分了!
"Kiss Aunt Emma"? Why, this is outrageous!
3美元的变化。为什么,我…你会喜欢的，你会喜欢的。
$3 change. Why, I... You'll love it, you'll love it.
3美元的变化。
$3 change.
为什么，小姐，我反对……这太离谱了!
Why, miss, I protest against... This is outrageous!
别紧张，法官。会没事的。非常感谢。
Take it easy, Judge. It'll be all right. Thank you very much.
现在，说真的，萨金特夫人，我认为这个笑话已经过去了……约翰·萨金特!
Now, really, Mrs. Sargent, I think that this joke has gone... John Sargent!
没人想逼你买东西，法官。
Nobody's trying to force you to buy anything, Judge.
我们只要保持通道畅通就行了。
We just have to keep the aisles clear.
可是，约翰，我反对这种做法!现在，约翰，我抗议!
But, John, I protest against it! Now, John, I protest!
穿着裤子去参加舞会!
Wearing pants to a dance!
她永远不会那样说服他的。
She'll never land him that way.
女人应该穿裙子!
Women belong in skirts!
让他们着迷的是神秘感。
It's the mystery that gets 'em.
我只是觉得这些更容易穿。
I just thought these would be easier to wear.
你的腰围有多大?
How big are you around the waist?
我不知道，大概25、26岁吧。
I don't know, 25, 26, I guess.
当我年轻的时候，我们认为19岁已经很大了。
When I was young, we thought 19 was big.
怎么会有人只有19岁?
How could anybody be 19?
好吧，这需要一点努力，但它可以做到!
Well, it takes a little pulling, but it can be done!
现在，呼气。
Now, let out your breath.
更多!来吧!
More! Come on!
现在，一，二，三!
Now, one, two, three!
现在，感觉如何?
Now, how does that feel?
你会习惯的。
You'll get used to it.
我们其他人都这么做了。
The rest of us did.
胡说!
Fiddlesticks!
现在把它系在你的腰上。
Now, tie that around your waist.
在我年轻的时候，我从来没有像我们应该拥有的那样拥有那么多的正面。
I never did have as much front as we were supposed to have in my day.
你不会真的把这些东西都穿了吧?
You didn't really wear all these things, did you?
当然，我们做到了。这仅仅是个开始。
Of course, we did. This is just the beginning.
这是紧身胸衣的封面。
Now, here's the corset cover.
把它系好。
Fasten it up.
好了。
There you go.
它是美丽的!
It's beautiful!
那是你的婚纱吗?
Was that your wedding dress?
有一年夏天，我一直在琢磨这个主意。
I twiddled around with the idea one summer.
到了秋天，我又好了。
I was all right again by fall.
谢谢你，亲爱的。
Thank you, dear.
李!阿姨艾玛!
Lee! Aunt Emma!
来了!来了!
Coming! Coming!
生者之地!
Land of the living!
在我们到达之前，舞会不会跑掉的!
The dance is not going to run away before we get there!
我只是不想让李错过…
Well, I just didn't want Lee to miss the...
天啊!
Gosh!
她很漂亮，不是吗?
She's beautiful, isn't she?
是的。
Yes.
他们会有非常可爱的孩子。
They'd have awful cute babies.
艾米，杰克没有恋爱。
Why, Emmy, Jack isn't in love.
你怎么会有这种想法?
Where did you get such an idea?
胡说!
Fiddlesticks!
好吧，我告诉你，他们不是。
Well, I tell you they're not.
我不会告诉你原因什么的，但是他们…他们就是不可能，仅此而已。
I'm not going to tell you why or anything, but they... Well, they just can't be, that's all.
艾米，你不知道这些事，如果我是你…露西·萨金特，如果你指的是我从未结过婚，
Emmy, you don't know about these things and if I were you... Lucy Sargent, if you're referring to the fact that I never married,
我想指出的是，你不必是一匹马来评判一场马展。
I'd like to point out that you don't have to be a horse to judge a horse show.
如果我曾经见过两个人…嘘!
If ever I saw two people that were... Shh!
几乎结束了。
Almost over.
时间过得真快，不是吗?
Gone quickly, hasn't it?
如此之快!
So quickly!
如果这还不像派克峰那么简单。
If that isn't as plain as Pikes Peak.
胡说!
Fiddlesticks!
你们都太贴心了。
You've all been so sweet.
不管我们回来后发生什么，都不重要了。
No matter what happens after we get back, it won't matter so much.
我会有一些美好的回忆。
I'll have some wonderful memories.
女士们，先生们!
Ladies and gentlemen!
我现在荣幸地祝你新年快乐!
I now have the honor to wish you a happy New Year!
应该忘记旧日的相识吗?
* Should auld acquaintance be forgot * And never brought to mind?
*应该忘记旧情人吗?*
* Should auld acquaintance be forgot * And auld lang syne? *
晚安，孩子们。甜蜜的梦想。
Good night, children. Sweet dreams.
我将在7点15分给你吃早餐。
I'll have your breakfast at 7:15.
你想要什么?法兰绒蛋糕还是炸糊?
What do you want? Flannel cakes or fried mush?
我想我们还是坐火车吧。
I think we'd ride better on the mush.
好吧。
All right.
新年快乐。
Happy New Year.
晚安，艾美。晚安，李。
Good night, Emmy. Good night, Lee.
晚安，艾美阿姨。
Good night, Aunt Emmy.
晚安，亲爱的。好好休息。
Good night, dear. Get a good rest.
晚安，各位。
Good night.
谢谢你！谢谢你所做的一切。
Thank you. Thank you for everything.
晚安，杰克。
Good night, Jack.
晚安，李。
Good night, Lee.
晚安，儿子。
Good night, son.
晚安，妈妈。
Good night, Mother.
祝新年万事如意。
The best of everything to you this New Year.
谢谢,妈妈。晚安，各位。
Thanks, Mom. Good night.
晚安，亲爱的。
Good night, dear.
你困了吗?
You sleepy?
不是很。
Not very.
你想去我房间抽根烟吗?
You want to come in my room and have a cigarette?
坐在火旁会很好。
It'd be nice by the fire.
嗯…
Well...
我马上就来。
I'll be in in a minute.
进来。
Come in.
很抱歉打扰你，亲爱的，但我知道你明天早上会有多匆忙。
I'm sorry to disturb you, dear, but I know how rushed you're going to be tomorrow morning.
你没有打扰我。
You're not disturbing me.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
首先，我想告诉您我们是多么高兴您能和我们在一起，我希望您在这里过得愉快。
First, I want to tell you how glad we are to have had you here with us, and how much I hope you've enjoyed your stay with us.
你永远不知道有多少。
You'll never know how much.
然后我想告诉你，你遇到麻烦，我是多么难过，我多么希望一切都会好起来。
And then I want to tell you how sorry I am that you're in trouble, and how much I hope everything'll come out all right.
我不知道你知道这事。
I didn't know you knew about that.
可怜的孩子，
You poor child,
我现在绝不会跟你提这件事，要不是……嗯…杰克跟你说过他的童年吗?
I never would have mentioned it to you now, only... Well... Did Jack ever tell you anything about his childhood?
不。为什么?
No. Why?
我丈夫死后，我们家很穷。
We were very poor after my husband died.
事实上，我们一无所有。
In fact, we had nothing.
杰克上学前要做家务，放学后也要做家务。
Jack had to do chores before school and chores after school.
上高中的时候，他下午开送货卡车赚点钱。
And when he was in high school, he drove a delivery truck afternoons to earn a little money.
然后，在做家务之后，他晚上学习，试图进入大学。
Then after chores he studied evenings to try to get into college.
他勤工俭学读完了大学，又勤工俭学读完了法学院。
He worked his way through college and he worked his way through law school.
我并不是想说这有什么不寻常的。
I'm not trying to say that there's anything unusual in that.
此刻，成千上万的男孩正在做同样的事情。
Thousands of boys are doing the same thing this minute.
但我想告诉你，他有多努力才取得今天的成就。
But I am trying to tell you how hard he worked to get where he is today.
非常非常难。
How very, very hard.
我认为我们现在不应该让任何事情破坏他的兴致。
And I don't think that we should allow anything to spoil it for him now.
我看不出有什么事会破坏他的兴致，你说呢?
I don't see why anything should spoil it for him, do you?
他爱上你了。
He's in love with you.
他没有爱上我。
He isn't in love with me.
他对我的兴趣就像你给那些乞丐买顿饭一样。
He's never had any more interest in me than some panhandler you buy a meal for.
你确定吗?
Are you sure?
当然，我敢肯定。
Of course, I'm sure.
但他今晚吻了你。
But he kissed you tonight.
好吧,我……我其实并不丑。
Well, I... I'm not exactly ugly.
他可能对我有点发烧，但不会有什么进展，也没有任何进展。
He may have a little fever for me, but it isn't going any further and it hasn't been any place, either.
他不是傻瓜。
He's no fool.
即使他是
And even if he was,
我不会伤害他，也不会伤害你，艾米阿姨，甚至威利。
I wouldn't hurt him or you, Aunt Emmy, or even Willie.
谢谢你，亲爱的。
Thank you, dear.
但你还是爱他的，对吧?
You do love him though, don't you?
恐怕是这样。
I'm afraid so.
这是你做的饼干。
Here's some of the cookies you made.
别忘了你是怎么做的。
Don't forget how you made them.
再见,妈妈。再见，艾美阿姨。
Goodbye, Mother. Goodbye, Aunt Emmy.
再见,约翰。见到你真是太好了。
Goodbye, John. It was awfully nice to see you.
再见。再见,威利。
Goodbye. Goodbye, Willie.
再见,亲爱的。
Goodbye, dear.
再见,威利。再见。
Goodbye, Willie. Goodbye.
再见，谢谢你所做的一切。
Goodbye, and thank you for everything.
我永远不会忘记。
I'll never forget it.
不用谢，亲爱的，有时间就回来吧。
You're quite welcome, dear, and come back whenever you can.
现在，穿上暖和的衣服。
Now, wrap up and keep good and warm.
小心开车，孩子。
Drive carefully, son.
你要经过斯克兰顿还是匹兹堡?
Are you going by way of Scranton or Pittsburgh?
通过加拿大!
Through Canada!
——再见。——再见。
- Bye. - Goodbye.
嘿，别忘了写信。
Hey, don't forget to write.
别忘了劈些木头。
Don't you forget to chop some wood.
现在圣诞节结束了。
Now Christmas is over.
这不是事实吗?
Ain't it the truth.
您有什么要申报的吗?不。
Have you anything to declare? No.
我在隆隆的座位上放了四瓶中国酒和一桶俄克莱豪酒，但仅此而已。
I have four Chinese and a barrel of okolehao in the rumble seat, but that's all.
你是哪里人?美国。
And where are you from? United States.
你出生在哪里?印第安纳州。
Where were you born? Indiana.
你是哪里人?美国。
And where are you from? United States.
你出生在哪里?印第安纳州。
Where were you born? Indiana.
你来加拿大的原因是什么?
And what is your reason for going through Canada?
我是个逃犯。
I'm a fugitive from justice.
你听起来像个疯人院的逃犯。
You sound like a fugitive from a nut house.
请讲，先生，请讲。
Go ahead, sir. Go ahead.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
你知道吗?
You know something?
怎么啦？
What?
你现在在加拿大。
You're in Canada now.
怎么了?
What about it?
如果你明天不想回去，我也没办法逼你。
If you didn't want to go back tomorrow, I couldn't make you.
你听到我说的话了吗?
Did you hear what I said?
我听到了。
I heard you.
你昨晚为什么不进来抽根烟?
Why didn't you come in for that cigarette last night?
我不想抽烟。
I didn't feel like smoking.
我希望你在法庭上看到我的时候不要笑出声来。
I hope you don't bust out laughing when you look at me in court.
我不太想笑。
I won't feel much like laughing.
你知道吗，有意思的是在法庭上的所有人里，你是唯一一个看起来有心的人。
You know, it's funny that of all the people in the courtroom, you were the only one that seemed to have a heart.
你还以为你是最后一个呢。
You'd think you'd be the last one.
别相信我。
Don't give me any credit.
我对你耍了个卑鄙的把戏，我觉得有点不好意思，仅此而已。
I played a fairly dirty trick on you and I felt a little bad about it, that's all.
你怎么跟我玩卑鄙的把戏?
How did you play me a dirty trick?
把你的案子推迟到假期之后。
By having your case put over till after the holidays.
当我看到陪审团要在圣诞节宣判你无罪时。
When I saw the jury was going to acquit you for Christmas.
为什么，你这个狗!
Why, you dog!
你真是太聪明了。
That was pretty smart of you all right.
这是生意的一部分。
Part of the business.
那个胖子把我弄出来是因为你良心不安。
Then when that fat slob got me out it was because your conscience was bothering you.
一点。
A little.
我一直以为是我的腿。
And all the time I thought it was my legs.
我都不知道你反对我。
I didn't even know you were against me.
我就知道你是想把我关进监狱什么的。
I knew you were supposed to be trying to put me in jail or something.
但是，我不知道，你看起来很温柔。
But, I don't know, you seemed so gentle.
这是技巧的一部分。
That's part of the technique.
如果你不小心对待女人，陪审团里的每个男人都想揍你的鼻子。
If you don't treat a woman with kid gloves, every man on the jury wants to punch you in the nose.
你也得小心翼翼地对付他们，否则你就会得到正确的判决。
You have to handle them with kid gloves, too, or you get it right in the verdict.
把一个女人关进监狱是很难的，不管她做了什么。
It's very hard to put a woman in jail, no matter what she's done.
我应该算是这方面的专家。
I'm supposed to be sort of a specialist at it.
不，你不是。我当然是。
No, you're not. Sure I am.
你只是想让我恨你这样你给我生意的时候就不会那么难受了，对吧?
You're just trying to make me hate you so you won't feel so bad when you give me the business, aren't you?
你是，不是吗?
You are, aren't you?
我是认真的。
I mean it.
我希望你不要再说废话了。
I wish you'd stop talking nonsense.
这不是废话。我不是警察。
It isn't nonsense. I'm not a policeman.
你回去不回去与我无关。
It's none of my business whether you go back or not.
不管怎样，我没有钱。
Anyway, I haven't any money.
你不用担心这个。
You wouldn't have to worry about that.
我能想象你的胖朋友如果他付了那五千美元会有多生气。
I can just see the fizz on your fat friend if he had to shell out that five grand.
你也不用担心这个。
You don't have to worry about that, either.
如果我想的话，我可以担心。
I can worry about it if I want to.
你是个优秀的地方检察官。
A fine district attorney you are.
你知道我爱你，对吧?
You know I love you, don't you?
别这么说。
Don't say that.
为什么我不该说呢?
Why shouldn't I say it?
就因为某个珠宝商说你偷了他的手镯吗?
Because some chiseling jeweler claims you swiped one of his bracelets?
我确实刷过了。
I did swipe it.
陪审团会告诉你你是否服用了。
The jury will tell you whether you took it or not.
他拿回来了，不是吗?
He got it back, didn't he?
不管怎样，你昨天做的和你今天做的是两回事。
Anyway, what you did yesterday and what you do today are two different things.
政府想让你做的就是剥夺别人的财产。
All the state wants you to do is lay off other people's property.
它不关心这个条件是如何达到的。
It doesn't care how that condition is arrived at.
一旦你和我在一起，你就不会做那些事了。
Once you were with me, you wouldn't pull any of that stuff.
我可能会。
I might.
把你的耳朵打趴下。
And get your ears knocked down.
拜托!
Please!
你爱我，对吧，李?
You love me, don't you, Lee?
不。
No.
我想这就是为什么你那样看着我，那样和我跳舞，那样吻我。
I suppose that's why you've looked at me the way you have and danced with me the way you did and kissed me the way you did.
为什么你的手总是牵着我的手，我的手总是牵着你的手，只要他们在一起。
Why your hand has always found mine and mine has always found yours whenever they're anywhere near each other.
不要上当受骗。
Don't be a sucker.
当然，你是个英俊的男人，而我只是个普通人，但你说的那些国家不在乎，或者我待在这里，或者我们在一起的时候我会是什么样子，都是胡扯。
Naturally you're a good-looking man and I'm only human, but everything you said about the state not caring, or my staying here, or how I'd be when we were together is the bunk.
你必须记住，你是如何努力工作才取得今天的成就，你是如何在放学后开着卡车，做着家务……我妈妈跟你谈过了，对吧?
You've got to remember how hard you worked to get where you are, and how you drove a truck after school, and did the chores... My mother's been talking to you, hasn't she?
她为什么不能呢?她有值得骄傲的事。
Why shouldn't she? She's got something to be proud of.
你也要感到自豪，好好想想，而不是告诉别人逃保释金……
And you've got to be proud and think about it, too, instead of telling people to jump bail and...
你很清楚……
You know perfectly well that...
不要不公平。
Don't be unfair.
我爱你，李。
I love you, Lee.
失去你对我来说太难了。
It'll be awfully hard to lose you.
你知道我希望什么吗?
You know what I wish?
怎么啦？
What?
我希望案子结束，你被无罪释放。
I wish the case was over and you'd been acquitted.
那你就不该推迟。
Then you shouldn't have had it postponed.
这是真的。
That's true.
但如果我没有，我就不会遇到你。
But if I hadn't, I wouldn't have met you.
这是真的。
That's true.
案子结束了，你被无罪释放了。
So the case is over and you've been acquitted.
敲木头。
Knock wood.
然后我拿出一张结婚证…哎呀……然后我们直接走进法官的办公室让他为我们主持婚礼。
And I pull out a marriage license... Gee... And we march right into the Judge's chambers and have him marry us.
你知道你说话像个四岁小孩，对吧?
You know you're talking like a four-year-old, don't you?
你知道我们要去哪里度蜜月吗?
You know where we're going for our honeymoon?
在哪里?尼亚加拉瀑布。
Where? Niagara Falls.
但我们现在到了，亲爱的。
But we're there now, darling.
你疯了，杰克。
You're crazy, Jack.
我以为一切都解决了。
I thought it was all settled.
那是在尼亚加拉大瀑布。
That was in Niagara Falls.
人们不用为他们在尼亚加拉大瀑布说的话负责。
People aren't responsible for what they say in Niagara Falls.
这里是纽约。这是今天，而且……
This is New York. This is today, and...
这是不同的。
This is different.
就像我艾米阿姨会说的那样，这是一根琴弦。
As my Aunt Emmy would say, fiddlesticks.
好吧，这不是小提琴。
Well, it isn't fiddlesticks.
首先，他们没有理由放我无罪即使他们放了我也不会嫁给你。
In the first place, there's no reason why they should acquit me and even if they did I wouldn't marry you.
你不再爱我了吗?
Don't you love me anymore?
我从来没有爱过你。
I never loved you.
你在跟我开玩笑吗?
Were you just toying with me?
闭嘴。
Shut up.
你必须对你未来的丈夫表现出更多的礼貌和尊重，否则我将不得不采取强硬措施。
You'll have to develop more courtesy and respect for your future husband, or I shall have to resort to strong measures.
一个女人，一条狗，一棵山核桃树，你打得越厉害，他们就越厉害
"A woman, a dog, a hickory tree, "the better you beat them, the better they be."
放弃它。你会吗?
Quit it. Will you?
好吧。怎么啦？
All right. What?
你知道这是不对的，杰克。
You know it isn't right, Jack.
你看不见报纸吗?
Can't you see the papers?
“地方检察官娶了一个骗子。”
"District Attorney marries girl crook."
为什么，我只会伤害你。
Why, I'd only hurt you.
你不记得法官看到我们在那里时的反应了吗?
Don't you remember how the judge acted when he saw us in that place?
但你不会是骗子，你会被无罪释放。
But you won't be a crook, you'll be acquitted.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know?
我不知道，但我觉得你机会很大。
Well, I don't know, but I think you've got a good chance.
你不会做任何事让他们放我无罪，对吧?
You wouldn't do anything to make them acquit me, would you?
我该怎么办呢?
What could I do?
那将是一件好事。
That would be a fine thing.
司机，请在下一个街角停一下，好吗?
Driver, stop at the next corner will you, a minute?
我们最好不要一起出去。
We'd better not get out together.
那就太过分了。是的。
That'd be pushing things too far. Yeah.
祝你好运，亲爱的。谢谢。
Good luck, honey. Thanks.
不要不开心。
Don't be unhappy.
我不是不开心，我只是很困惑。
I'm not unhappy, I'm all confused.
一切都会好的。
Everything's going to come out all right.
结果一定会很好!
It's got to come out all right!
让我在街区中间下车，好吗?
Let me out in the middle of the block, will you?
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
我告诉你，我确实看到他们了。
I tell you, I did see them.
在咖啡馆跳舞。
Dancing in a cafe.
就在他在这个法庭起诉她两小时之后。
Two hours after he was prosecuting her in this very court.
我告诉你，你错了。
And I tell you you're mistaken.
那孩子死在平地上了。
That boy's dead on the level.
如果他不像现在这样诚实，我会说他在政治上很有前途。
And if he weren't quite as honest as he is, I'd say he had a big future in politics.
我站得离他们很近……你忘了你已经是个老头了。
I stood as close to them... You forget that you're an old man.
你的眼睛不像以前那么好了。
Your eyes aren't as good as they used to be.
我对他说话，他回答我。
As it happens, I spoke to him and he answered me.
任何人都会回答你。那只是一般的礼貌。
Anybody would answer you. That's only common politeness.
我叫他杰克。
I called him Jack.
为什么，有成千上万的人叫杰克。
Why, there are millions of people called Jack.
你站不住脚。
You haven't got a leg to stand on.
你想立案起诉这个男孩。
You're trying to make a case against this boy.
都准备好了，法官大人。
All ready, Your Honor.
马上就来。
Be right in.
所以我猜你现在认为他会放弃这个案子。
So now I suppose you think he's going to throw the case.
那是你说的，亨利，不是我说的。
Those are your words, Henry, not mine.
我告诉你，就算他在给自己的兄弟打官司他也不会放弃。
I tell you, he wouldn't throw a case if he were trying his own brother.
如果你在法庭上，他不会的。
Not if you're in court, he wouldn't.
好吧，那我在这里听。
All right, then, I'll listen from here.
这就是我想要的。
That's all I wanted.
还有你的道歉。
That and your apology later.
你会打到猪眼睛里的。
You'll get that in a pig's eye.
听着，听着，听着。
Hear ye, hear ye, hear ye.
纽约县最高法院普通会议庭现在开庭。
The Court of General Sessions, Division of the Supreme Court of New York County is now in session.
法官大人，我是沃克法官。
His Honor, Judge Walker, presiding.
你听过凯因梅茨医生描述过这种被称为“催眠猝倒”的情况吗?
You heard Dr. Keinmetz describe the condition known as hypnoleptic catalepsies?
是的,先生。
Yes, sir.
你认为这就是你当时的状况吗?
Would you say that is the condition you were in?
我想是的。是的,先生。
I guess so. Yes, sir.
这是所有。
That's all.
请稍等，利安德小姐。
Just a moment, please, Miss Leander.
你说你离开珠宝店走第五大道的时候被催眠了。
Now, you said that you were hypnotized at the time you left the jewelry store and walked up 5th Avenue.
不是吗?
Didn't you?
嗯…你到底有没有?
Well... Did you or didn't you?
我的律师是这么说的。
Well, my lawyer said so.
你的律师这么说的?
Your lawyer said so?
那么我们是否可以理解你和你的律师对发生的事情意见不一致?
Are we to understand then that you and your lawyer do not agree exactly as to what happened?
别回答那个问题!
Don't answer that question!
我反对，法官大人!这个问题非常不恰当，无关紧要，无关紧要，我要求将其从记录中删除。
I object, Your Honor! The question is highly improper, irrelevant, immaterial, and I ask it be stricken from the record.
持续。
Sustained.
陪审团将忽略这个问题。
The jury will disregard the question.
你是不是被催眠了?
Were you hypnotized or weren't you?
我想……我们不想听你的猜测。
I suppose... We don't want your suppositions.
我们想知道你是不是被催眠了。
We want to know whether you were hypnotized or not.
是的。
Yes.
是的什么?
Yes what?
我想我是被催眠了。
I guess I was hypnotized.
你猜你被催眠了?
You guess you were hypnotized?
一开始你以为自己被催眠了，现在你又觉得自己被催眠了。
First you suppose you were hypnotized and now you guess you were.
请记住你是发过誓的，利安德小姐。
Kindly remember you are under oath, Miss Leander.
你知道作伪证的处罚吗?
Do you know the penalty for perjury?
-我反对，法官阁下——持续。
- I object, Your Honor. - Sustained.
别那么粗鲁，杰克。我告诉过你多少次，当你和一个女人一起工作时…到底是哪一个呢?猜测还是假设?
Not so rough, Jack. How many times have I told you when you're working with a woman... Well, which is it? A guess or a supposition?
他为什么这么强硬?
What's he getting so tough about?
他天生就是刻薄的。
He's just naturally mean.
我接手了一个谋杀案，他们没那么粗暴。
I sat on a murder case and they didn't get that rough.
法官大人，这些陪审员又在喋喋不休了。
Your Honor, these jurors are gabbing again.
陪审员们将停止窃窃私语，把全部注意力放在手头的案子上。
The jurors will cease whispering and give their entire attention to the case at hand.
继续。利安德小姐，你能告诉我们被催眠是什么感觉吗?
Proceed. Miss Leander, will you kindly tell us how it feels to be hypnotized?
——对象。——持续。
- Object. - Sustained.
你几岁开始偷东西的?
How old were you when you began to steal things?
——对象。——持续。
- Object. - Sustained.
那和这件事有什么关系?
What's that got to do with this?
只是想把她弄糊涂。
Just trying to get her in wrong.
法官大人，那些陪审员又来了。
Your Honor, those jurors are at it again.
萨金特先生。
Mr. Sargent.
我完全有能力在没有律师的情况下管理这个法庭。
I am perfectly capable of running this courtroom without prompting from counsel.
如果陪审员中再有人窃窃私语，我就判他们藐视法庭。
If there's any more whispering among the jurors, I'll hold the offenders in contempt.
现在继续这个案子。
Now proceed with this case.
你被美丽的珠宝催眠过多少次?
How many times have you been hypnotized by beautiful jewelry?
对象。我想是很多次吧。
Object. I guess quite a lot of times.
请不要在我反对之后再回答问题。
Please don't answer questions after I've objected to them.
反对持续。
Objection sustained.
陪审团将忽略问题和答案。
The jury will disregard the question and the answer.
你听过凯因梅兹医生对催眠的看法吗?
Did you hear Dr. Keinmetz's opinion about hypnotism?
请你回答我的问题，不要让我们在这里等一整天好吗?
Will you kindly answer my question and not keep us waiting here all day?
你能回答我的问题吗?
Will you answer my question?
法官大人，如果证人拒绝回答我的问题我也无能为力了。
Your Honor, if the witness refuses to answer my questions there's nothing more I can do.
请囚犯回答律师的问题。
The prisoner will please answer counsel's question.
我可以把手帕借给你吗?
May I lend you my handkerchief?
你的荣誉……请把你的答案写在这里给我。
Your Honor... Kindly address your answers to me over here.
法官大人，我想请求…法官大人，我觉得这位女士身体不太好。
Your Honor, I want to plead... Your Honor, I don't believe this young lady is well.
我想五分钟的休庭应该是……但我想认罪。
I think a five-minute recess would be... But I want to plead guilty.
毫无疑问，是我让她……拜托,杰克。你的荣誉!
I am undoubtedly responsible for having made her... Please, Jack. Your Honor!
休庭几分钟，法官大人。
Just a few minutes recess, Your Honor.
这个年轻女人歇斯底里。很明显，她正处于一种情绪的痛苦之中，在这种情绪中，她对自己说的话不负责。
This young woman is hysterical... She's quite obviously in the throes of an emotion during which she's not responsible for what she says.
我很好。我只想认罪。
I'm all right. I just want to plead guilty.
法官大人，请允许我们休庭五分钟。
If Your Honor would kindly grant a five-minute recess.
我的孩子，你为什么要认罪?
My child, why do you want to plead guilty?
因为我有罪。
Because I am guilty.
当你犯了错误，你就得为此付出代价。
And when you make a mistake you've got to pay for it.
否则，你永远学不会。
Otherwise, you never learn.
法官大人，很明显这不是正常行为。
Your Honor, it must be apparent this is not normal conduct.
很明显。国家也不希望利用暂时的失常作为愚蠢的……这不是暂时的。
Quite apparent. And the state has no wish to take advantage of a temporary aberration as stupid... There isn't anything temporary about this.
你能看出来我脑子是正常的，对吧?
You can see that I'm in my right mind, can't you?
既然这样，那就没什么可说的了。
Well, in that case, there's nothing more to be said.
现在开庭时间定在下周五，1月6日，上午10点。
The court at this time will set next Friday, January the 6th, at 10:00 a.m.
作为通过判决的时间。
as time for passing sentence.
犯人被还押到市监狱。
The prisoner is remanded to the city jail.
谢谢你，法官大人。
Thank you, Your Honor.
我以为审判至少要持续一个星期。
I thought the trial would last at least a week.
陪审团解散。
The jury is dismissed.
好吗?
Well?
我不知道。
I don't know.
妇女吗?
Matron?
你知道你做了什么吗?
Do you know what you've done?
你知道这是无法挽回的吗?
Do you realize it can't be undone?
你知道没有上诉，没有重审，没有无效审判，只有监狱!
You understand there's no appeal, no retrial, no mistrial, nothing but jail!
我能得到多长时间?
How long will I get?
我怎么知道?
How do I know?
也许你活不了多久，但如果你闭上你的陷阱，你就根本不用去了。
Maybe you won't get very long, but if you'd kept your trap shut you wouldn't have to go at all.
没有别的事可做了。
There wasn't anything else to do.
你还不明白吗?
Don't you see?
你很坚强，也很会辩，而我…我很爱你。
You're so strong, and you argue so well and I... I love you so much.
你确实证明了这一点。
You certainly proved that.
我总是做你想做的事，即使这对你不好。
I'd always do what you wanted, even if it wasn't good for you.
我永远不会有机会对抗你而你也永远不会有机会和我在一起。
I'd never have a chance against you and you'd never have a chance with me.
就像刚才，你差点输掉官司的时候。
Like just now, when you were trying to lose the case.
你不觉得羞耻吗?
Aren't you ashamed?
废话。
Hogwash.
我知道你想干什么。
I know what you were trying to do.
把小威利的事业从坏女人手里拯救出来。
Save little Willie's career from the bad, bad woman.
你这个可怜的笨蛋，难道你不认为我是最能判断什么对我好，什么是我在这个世界上最想要的吗?
You poor sap, don't you think I'm the best judge of what's good for me and what I want most in this world?
不。
No.
当你摆出高贵姿态的时候，你有没有想过你伤我有多深?
And when you were making your grand gesture, did you stop to think how much you were hurting me?
你以为我不会再爱你了就因为他们把你和一群徒步旅行者和瘾君子关在一起几年吗?
Do you think I'm going to stop loving you just because they lock you up with a bunch of hikers and hopheads for a few years?
我也好不到哪里去。
I'm not much better.
你配得上我。
You're good enough for me.
你什么时候来看我好吗?
Will you come and see me sometime?
来看你吗?
Come and see you?
我现在就去找法官，给你主持婚礼。
I'm going to send for the judge and marry you right now.
不过还是要谢谢你。
But thank you just the same.
如果你之后还想要我。
If you still wanted me afterwards.
这样我就扯平了，你就有足够的时间考虑了。
I'd be all square and you would have had plenty of time to think things over.
很多事情。
Lots of things.
将……当他们判决我的时候，你会站在我身边握着我的手吗?
Will... Will you stand beside me and hold my hand when they sentence me?
当然，我会的。
Of course, I will.
那我就不会害怕了。
Then I won't be afraid.
我如此爱你。
I love you so.